Chapter 1: A New Story Unfolds in Laoravia

I swore something?

What did I swear again?

Slowly, I opened my eyes and sat up. My head felt heavy as I scanned the room.

“Where am I?”

It was no place I recognized. The wooden room was cramped, with the bare minimum in the way of furnishings. There was one wide-open window, through which a cool breeze was blowing. The room was modest, sure, but it was relaxing too.

There was one other man in the room. He bore sharp features, and he was seated in a chair that constituted one of the very few pieces of furniture. From what I remembered, his name was...Palinchron.

Ah, right. It’s Palinchron Regacy. I owe this man my life!

Upon seeing me rise from my sleep, he closed the book he was holding, patting me amicably on the shoulder.

“Oh? You’re up now, are you, Kanami? Good timing. Your sister just woke up too. I’ll take ya over to her.”

With that, he exited the room. I got down from the bed and made to follow him. Then, my body stiffened. It was an unpleasant sensation.

Something’s off.

It was like my wires were crossed. Like the limbs on my doll had been swapped around. But accompanying that pall of unease was a distinctly refreshing sense of liberation. I could practically feel the breeze through the gaping hole that had been opened up in my heart. I had a hunch that I was misconstruing something important—that I’d forgotten something essential. But I also got the sense that I had that very fact to thank for feeling so light on my feet. It was a weird sensation.

“Kanami! Would you come already?!”

At his urging, that sensation dissipated. I could hardly keep the man to whom I owed so much waiting, so I chose not to brood over it.

“Ah, my bad, Palinchron! I’m coming!” I said, exiting out the door myself.

When my eyes met the hallway, I remembered where I was—the headquarters of the guild called Epic Seeker. The room I had just been in was a guild medical office, where I’d been getting some rest. It boggled my mind that I could have failed to realize it the second I got up, but no amount of standing there puzzling over it would do me any good. After all, Palinchron was walking in the distance, and if I didn’t catch up, I was fairly sure he’d just leave me in the dust without mercy. So I quickly marched down this hallway, which I knew I was supposed to be familiar with, but felt totally new to me.

As I walked, I realized that I wasn’t operating at a hundred percent. I felt languid, as though I’d been asleep for days and days...and I was in a trancelike state of mind, like I was treading on air. I could even truthfully say that I still felt like I was in a dream. I kept shaking my head as I followed in Palinchron’s wake.

After climbing some stairs, I made it to the threshold of a certain room. Palinchron was standing in front of the entrance, beckoning me inside. I opened the door to find a chamber far more spacious than that medical office. At a glance, it was around five times bigger. Several bookshelves lined the wall, lending the room an intellectual air. On the far opposite side lay one large bed. Atop it sat a young girl with black hair. She was staring out the window, through the swaying curtains.

Ah, of course. This girl is the girl I swore to...

“Your sister, Mar-Mar, is also doing good,” came Palinchron’s voice from behind me. “Bet you’re relieved, huh, Kanami?”

My...sister? Yes, yes of course. This black-haired girl is my little sister. The most important person to me. I have to protect her even if it costs me my life. The sister who our dearly departed mother entrusted to me. And her name... Her name’s Maria.

“Uh, yeah...I’m so relieved that Maria’s safe and sound too.”

For some reason, saying the name Maria sent a shooting pain through my head.

“Yep, the fire was pretty big, but we’re okay. In fact, it seems not one person got hurt.”

As he spoke, I gradually snapped out of my half-slumber more and more. That’s right. Palinchron saved Maria and me from that fire.

I was slipping out of my trance, the memories coming back to me. One after the other, my misadventures in this fantasy world surged back into my mind. This was the second time Palinchron had saved me. When the two of us had first stumbled into this unfamiliar world, he had been there to save us from the perils of the Dungeon. That was the first time. The second time was when he had rescued us from the great big fire in town. I could remember seeing my house burning to the ground. That memory alone, I remembered vividly.

I was surprised, however, to hear that no one had gotten hurt. I could have sworn that the fire had yielded one or two casualties.

“Kanami? You’ve come to see me?” She looked my way.

“Yep, it’s me. You seem like you’re already over it, Maria.”

“I guess you could say that, but...”

As we conversed, a sense of relief so deep that it was almost strange enveloped me.

“Got any injuries?”

“No, no injuries, but...” She put a hand to her head. “For some reason, my head hurts.”

That was nothing out of the ordinary for her. Ever since she was young, her body had been frail, and she had spent many a day in the hospital. That hadn’t improved once she’d come to this world. In fact, the sudden change in environment may have made it even worse.

Just then, I noticed the accessory she was wearing on her arm. It was the bangle that Palinchron had given her in order to mitigate all the inconveniences she would’ve faced as an outworlder. As long as we had our bangles on, we could conform to the environments this world threw at us, and we’d have no trouble following the language either. Apparently, my bangle also worked to stabilize my magic energy, which had a tendency to flare up wildly.

We had asked Palinchron how much our two bangles had cost, but he never said. They couldn’t have been cheap, that was for sure. And there was yet more that we owed him for. Maria’s eyes were artificial. As she had lost them in the fire, our host had prepared a pair for her. I could tell at a glance how expensive they must have been, considering their sheer perfection.

I’ve gotta keep doing my best if I ever want to repay Palinchron for his kindness. I was thinking that as I stroked Maria’s head and laid her down. “If your head’s hurting, you can rest a bit longer.”

“Okay. Thank you very much, Kanami.”

She blushed and let herself be laid down. As one might expect, she wasn’t feeling so great after all. In fact, it looked to me like she was running a fever. She had always had a chronic tendency to develop fevers.

I gripped her hand out of worry until Palinchron interrupted from behind.

“Mind leaving your heartwarming sibling reunion at that? We’ve got a ton of things to do today.”

“Things to do? Sorry, Palinchron, remind me: what are we doing today?”

“Today’s the day you’re set to enroll in Epic Seeker. You know, your guild? That fire almost made us forget, but since you appear to be fit as a fiddle, we’ll do it as planned.”

“Oh, right, I forgot.”

I remembered now. I needed to cover the costs of Maria’s medical expenses, so I had to make money. Enter Palinchron, who had referred me to this guild hustle a little while ago.

Epic Seeker was a guild officially recognized by the government of Laoravia, one of the nations within the Dungeon Alliance. And given my skills, I had the chops to work as one of their number, or so I was told.

“Oh, that’s right,” said Maria. “You’re going to be joining the guild.”

“You bet,” said Palinchron. “You two rascals do need to earn some money while you’re in this world. And I figured the best way to do that is for you to become part of my guild. Not only will you rake in some decent scratch, you’ll also gain connections. And best of all, you’ll be under Laoravia’s protection, which is a sweet deal for you two. It’s the ideal setup to get Mar-Mar the care she needs at the pace she needs, wouldn’t you say?”

As far as gigs went, it was perfect. “Thank you, Palinchron. Thanks to you, we can make a living in this world.”

“Now, now, let’s not get assured of ourselves too quickly,” he replied. “We’ll be having you take the entrance exam. We won’t let you in sight unseen just ’cause you’re you. If you don’t pass the test, there’s no deal.”

“That goes without saying. And you don’t have to spare me any sympathy when judging me either.” I couldn’t ask for better.

Palinchron grinned at how dripping with determination I sounded. “Over here.”

After bidding Maria goodbye, I followed after him so as to take the exam to be a part of Epic Seeker and obtain a place where we could eke out a life in this parallel world.

◆◆◆◆◆

The walls were made of stone, and the ceiling was atrium-style. A circular space cut out from the surrounding area was blanketed by softish sand. This was the training grounds of Epic Seeker, and it was about the size of a school’s grounds. Around thirty individual members of the guild, male and female, young and old, were gathered there. Some were toting swords bigger than they were, while others were carrying staffs or wands and clad in old-fashioned robes.

I was being stared at by thirty gazes, in a cold sweat right next to Palinchron, who, after seeing that everybody was present and saying a few words of greeting, pushed me forward.

“All right, Kanami, introduce yourself.”

“Er, um, my name is Aikawa Kanami. I’m a Level 14 ice mage. And I use a sword too, I guess. It’s nice to meet you...” I said, speaking so that they could all hear me.

The guild members reacted in a variety of ways. Some listened earnestly, while others weren’t paying attention. That being said, a lot of faces lit up when I mentioned my level.

“Level 14, at your age? Looks like Palinchron’s nabbed us a capable kid again.”

“And he’s polite too,” said one of the women. “Not to mention handsome. The burn mark on his neck’s a bit of a shame, though.”

“A mage who uses a sword, huh? I dunno. He might be chasing two rabbits there.”

They were not shy about their appraisals, and that didn’t feel great. It was like I was a piece of meat on display, and I prayed for it to be over soon. As I scanned everyone’s reactions, I noticed someone reacting in a conspicuous and odd way. A girl with long hair as wavy as the sea was goggling at me. I could tell from the horns poking out of her pretty hair that she was a semifer. She also had a tail sticking out from under her thick, tribal-style garb, removing all doubt.

“Huh? Mr. Sieg?” she said as she stared at me with amazement, her mouth agape.

“Oh, you’re here too, Snow...” said Palinchron. “Sorry,” he added to me, “go greet the guild members.” Then he headed over to the semifer girl, whose name was evidently Snow, to talk to her. He was one of the guild’s top members, so perhaps he had some kind of message or information for her.

As I was watching Palinchron and Snow discuss something at length, one of the other guild members approached me. “Hey there, Kanami. It’s nice to meet you too.”

I couldn’t very well keep looking to the side now. I promptly replied, trying to make as good of an impression as possible. “Thank you. I look forward to working with you.”

The other guild members saw that as their cue to approach me as well.

“Hiya, Kanami,” said one woman. “My name is Tayly. I’m also a party leader.”

“Ah, don’t go stealing a march on me. Listen, boy, I’m gonna teach ya the sword later. Don’t waste your time with magic. Actually, just join my party while you’re at it.”

“Whoa there, stop tryin’ to wedge somebody with magic energy into your meathead mold...”

“Welcome, Kanami!”

A mage with a cheery expression, a giant swordsman, a young man with a bow at his back—they were dressed like the setup for some walks-into-a-bar joke. I mean, I’d known I was in a fantasy world, but when they sidled up this close, it was enough to give me a bit of a start.

“Aha ha,” I said, forcing a smile. “I look forward to working with all of you...” I was a tad worried that my face looked too stiff.

“All right, everybody; settle down,” said Palinchron, clapping his hands to attract their attention as he walked closer to me.

It seemed he had finished saying whatever he needed to say to the semifer named Snow. The girl had moved even farther away, and now she was sitting in the shade. I wanted to go greet her too if possible, and not just because she was so easy on the eyes. For some reason, I got the feeling that talking to her was important. Strangely enough, I could have sworn I had already met her someplace.

“Kanami’s entrance exam isn’t over yet,” Palinchron continued. “Don’t you think you’re being a little hasty, fellas?”

Now that he’d started talking about my test, all thoughts about the girl flew away and I focused my mind. For the sake of my little sister as well as myself, I couldn’t afford to fail.

“Oh c’mon, Palinchron,” said the giant swordsman. “None of the folks you’ve brought here have ever failed the test. Let’s just skip that fluff. Put him right in my party, would ya?”

Judging from where the man was standing and what he’d just said, I figured he must bear a fairly high position. And the scars all over his body signaled that he was no pushover.

“We can’t know that for sure, can we?” answered Palinchron, never breaking his stride even as more heckling came his way. “In any case, I have an important announcement to make, so let’s pipe down for now.”

When I had first heard the guild was under direct government administration, I’d imagined a stuffier, more rigid atmosphere than this. The air here was very cozy.

“Whatever, just get it over with,” said a woman holding a staff as she smiled at me. “Just so you know, I’m taking him for my party.”

Palinchron ignored their bickering over whose party I’d be in. “I hate to break it to you, but Kanami’s not joining anybody’s party.”

At that, the guild members started talking among themselves with puzzled looks, and they all asked him to explain himself. Palinchron, however, did things at his own pace. When he replied, it was quite concise, and he explained his reasoning with relish.

“I’ll tell you why. It’s because Kanami’s gonna be Epic Seeker’s guildmaster.”

It took a beat for what he had said to sink in with the crowd. After a few seconds of silence, the training grounds were inundated by surprised outbursts. And the first to utter anything was me.

“Wait, what?!”

“Wait, hold up a sec,” said another guild member. “You’re taking the joke too far, Palinchron!”

“What in blazes?! What do ya mean he’s gonna be guildmaster?!”

I felt the same way. It sounded like nothing more than a bad prank to me. But Palinchron was as unruffled as ever.

“Kanami’s the hero handpicked by me and my fellow submaster, Rayle. Just as we planned from the outset, we’ll have a great hero of legend like Kanami take up the post at the very top of Epic Seeker.”

That was the second time he had definitively declared that he was aiming to make me guildmaster. And to top it off, he had even cast me as a “great hero.” Talk about hyperbole.

“You outta your mind?” asked the giant swordsman, who stood at the head of the crowd, glaring at him.

When it was clear that Palinchron was not, in fact, joking, the air started to get chillier. The atmosphere was tense, and things threatened to break down at the drop of a pin.

“Kanami’s strong, and he’s got a winning personality. But more importantly, he’s got the qualities of a hero. As such, it’s only proper that we should make him guildmaster. If anybody’s got a problem with that, feel free to get flattened by the lad. ’Cause instead of the entrance exam, we’re doing a round-robin tournament.”

Palinchron’s provocation only stirred more bloodlust in his audience. Every one of them glared white-hot daggers at us. I could scarcely handle the pressure these veterans and powerhouses were throwing at me.

“Palinchron, what’re you talking about?! Are you stupid or something?!”

Upon seeing me so confused and against the idea, a portion of the pressure died down.

One woman calmly took a step forward and offered her two cents. “I acknowledge his talents. I can tell just by looking at him that he’s competent. And I acknowledge that in the future, he may just stand above me. But to make him guildmaster from the jump is simply absurd, Palinchron.”

“There’s no way a guild that’s forced to work under a master who was thrust upon them will function properly...”

They must have concluded that if they let things come to a boil, a fight would break out, so they attempted to get Palinchron to change his mind with reason and logic. Reason and logic that Palinchron paid no heed to.

“Epic Seeker is always absurd and unreasonable. And I think you’ll all fall in line one way or another, seeing as Kanami’s the very person we’ve been so eagerly waiting for.”

He had no intention of backing down, and that was the spark that lit the powder keg. The whole lot of them made the preparations they needed to persuade him not with words but by force, gripping their respective weapons and taking a step forward as they shot him baleful stares.

“Don’t look at me that way. If any of you can manage to give Kanami a nick in the tournament that’ll be starting shortly, I’ll change my mind.”

“No taking that back.”

“Don’t look down on us!”

“If that boy winds up dead, it’s on you!”

They backed away from him as they issued their pointed remarks. Since they were each members of a larger organization, they didn’t defy Palinchron, who was above them in rank. But it was clear that they intended to vent their displeasure by means of the tournament. I had braced myself for a test, but I’d had no inkling that something like this would unfold.

“Hold on!” I said. “Wait, Palinchron, just hold on! I never agreed to this! They’re totally right. Me being made guildmaster from out of nowhere is ridiculous!”

“Wait, but didn’t you say you’d join the guild?”

“I mean, yeah, but as a normal member!”

“Well, I never said you’d be joining as a member. The whole time we were talking about it, I always meant to make you guildmaster.”

“Excuse me?! You... You tricked me!”

“Hey, don’t give people the wrong idea. I never lied to you...although people do call me a swindler all the time.”

Palinchron didn’t appear to mind being called a liar. He set about making the arrangements for the tournament as he fended off my attempts to talk him down, drawing lines in the sand with his scabbard and creating quick and simple field markers. When he finished, he turned to face me and pleaded with me, his expression the most earnest it had been that day.

“Please, Kanami. Please be guildmaster for me. The real stuff is yet to come. This doesn’t even register as a trial yet. Knowing you, I’m confident you can overcome hairier trials than this.”

In the face of such earnestness, I had no words. I wanted to repay the debt I owed him in some form, and moreover, I couldn’t refuse such a genuine request. All I could do was heave a sigh and nod reluctantly.

“All right, fine. I’ll fight in the tournament...but when it’s over, if the others aren’t convinced, then please let the guildmaster thing go.”

“Sounds good. Guess we’ve reached a compromise. But do me a favor: don’t go easy on them.”

“I don’t want to insult them, so I won’t hold back. For the most part...”

Upon my caving in, Palinchron went to the edge of the grounds and fetched me a blade that seemed to be for the purposes of training. He flung it at me and I caught it.

“Wintermension,” I muttered.

I deployed the spell that was my specialty, then mustered my resolve and stepped onto the battlefield. The sight of the bulging veins on the foreheads of the guild members left me feeling dejected.

“Wish I could’ve gotten an office job...like filing documents or something,” I grumbled as I unsheathed my sword, knowing that dream was not to be.

◆◆◆◆◆

My first bout was against a hot-blooded female swordfighter. She was on the younger side compared to her fellow members.

“He doesn’t warrant the party leader taking part,” she told the hulking swordsman before joining me on the battlefield.

Using my menu-sight, I perused the rapier wielder’s stats. She was at Level 12, and her sole skill was Swordplay. A pure swordfighter was no match for me.

As always, my abilities were practically cheating. I could only see the status menus of this world’s living things, but even so, that gave me more than enough of an unfair advantage. Having ascertained the girl’s strengths, I leisurely held my sword at the ready. If I wanted to, I could dispel all of my support magic and she’d still pose no challenge for me. While she was at a level where her physical capabilities were relatively high, there was nothing about her that was particularly noteworthy.

“Right then: Battle 1,” said Palinchron. “Start!”

At the signal, my opponent rushed me. “Raaaaaah!”

For the time being, I reckoned I’d keep to my promise—no holding back. First, I bumped the bottom of her sword’s hilt with the bottom of mine to disarm her without wounding her hand. At the same time, I swept her legs and snatched her sword out of the air with my left hand before thrusting both blades right before her eyes as she lay on the ground. Checkmate. The chasm between our speed and dexterity was just too great. Taking her weapon from her had proved a breeze.

“Huh? Wait, what... What happened?”

“So, I win, right?” I asked Palinchron.

“Yep, that’s a win in your column any way you slice it. Right then, neeext.”

The guild members were now wearing grim expressions, and no one immediately volunteered. They’d borne witness to one facet of my power; they must have come to understand this would be no walk in the park.

Just thinking about the duels to come made me feel gloomy. I took the poor girl by the hand and helped her up. “You okay?”

“Huh? Ah, yeah. I’m fine,” she replied, still in a daze as she let me pull her back to her feet. It must have finally sunk in that she’d lost. She stared at my face. “So this... This is the stuff of the ‘hero’ that Palinchron and Mr. Rayle chose?”

Her words had a bizarre zeal to them. A chill ran down my spine, so I used Dimension: Calculash to avoid her gaze. Then I hurried away from her. Since I wanted this tournament business over with quickly, I waited on the battlefield for the next challenger, who turned out to be another female fighter. In this world of levels and magic, there was no real difference between the strength of men and women when it came to fighting prowess. On the other hand, I did prefer male opponents—I couldn’t help but find it difficult to point blades at members of the opposite sex.

【STATUS】

NAME: Tayly Linkar

HP: 212/222

MP: 201/205

CLASS: Mage

LEVEL 19

STR 4.41

VIT 5.15

DEX 3.32

AGI 3.21

INT 7.21

MAG 11.09

APT 1.33

INNATE SKILLS: Wind Magic 1.67

ACQUIRED SKILLS: Magical Combat 1.12

Her menu and her outfit made it clear: I was fighting a trueborn mage now. Yet her physical capabilities were by no means inferior to the swordfighter I had fought before her. I didn’t doubt that this Tayly person was a member of high standing in Epic Seeker. Presumably, after watching my fight with the rapier girl, the others had realized they couldn’t hold back against me. With a few brief words, Ms. Tayly convinced her fellow challengers to let her take me on, and then she entered the proverbial ring.

I felt bad for her. Considering our stats, it’d be a miracle if she so much as touched me. What’s more, a pure magic build was especially ineffective against me.

“Aaand,” said Palinchron, “start!”

I closed the distance between us. Naturally, Ms. Tayly, being a mage, tried to craft a spell and clinch the battle before I could get near her. But my Wintermension wouldn’t let that happen. The spell she formulated shifted askew, releasing nothing more than the most attenuated of winds.

“Huh?! My spell!”

I put my blade to her throat. “Er, do you still want to fight, or...?”

A pause. “I surrender,” she replied, a terribly grim look on her face.

The giant swordsman spoke to her as she left the arena. “Hey, what happened in there? You couldn’t use your magic?”

“He has powerful inhibitor magic. A second and it was over, so that’s all I know.”

The giant swordsman silenced the rest of the group with a few words before entering the makeshift arena. Just like Ms. Tayly, he clearly held a great amount of sway.

【STATUS】

NAME: Vohlzark Aldo

HP: 340/351

MP: 0/0

CLASS: Swordfighter

LEVEL 20

STR 10.40

VIT 5.85

DEX 8.26

AGI 10.31

INT 7.09

MAG 0.00

APT 1.12

INNATE SKILLS: Defiant 1.21

ACQUIRED SKILLS: Swordplay 1.56

From the look of it, Mr. Vohlzark boasted the highest level among all the challengers. Inferring from the glances the people around him gave him, he was the most trusted of the long-serving veteran swordfighters, or of similar status. He radiated that sort of imposing air of dignity.

Mr. Vohlzark slung a strikingly huge longsword across his back and spoke to me. “Sorry, kid, but I’m going all out. I’ve got nothing against you personally. In fact, beating you will serve to teach ya a valuable lesson. The very idea of you becoming guildmaster so abruptly is bound to stoke resentment.”

Belying his scarred and colossal frame, his words were gentle and compassionate. His menu told me that his INT was on par with the mage I had just battled. I surmised he was a man of intellect.

“You’re a kind soul. Thank you, sir.” I bowed slightly. I was grateful toward him for showing so much consideration for the newbie who’d raised so many hackles.

Mr. Vohlzark heaved a sigh. “If it weren’t for how unreasonable that idiot submaster’s being, I’d be welcoming you with open arms,” he said as he closed the distance between us.

Palinchron took that as his cue. “Start!” he said gleefully.

At that, Mr. Vohlzark started running. He was faster than his hulking frame suggested. It felt like I was being rushed by some huge bull or bear. In a flash, he drew close, then swung his enormous sword at me from the side.

If I blocked his blow with the sword I was holding, my blade alone would break, so I distanced myself and evaded the attack by a nose.

“Tch! You won’t dodge this one!”

In order to break my sword, he swung his about like a raging storm. I could sense that on the whole, he wasn’t going easy on me. A direct hit would instantly kill any normal person. Yet at the same time, I didn’t sense a scrap of bloodlust from him. It seemed he was attacking me in this way because he’d concluded that I could take it. I could sense that this was the moment—if I sustained an “accidental” injury and ended this exam here and now, that’d suit me just fine.

Before we’d begun, I’d thought that against stalwarts who were so experienced, I’d at least get nicked at some point. But at this rate, I might actually end up actually beating them all without a scratch. I had shut down a top-class mage like Ms. Tayly completely, and the highest-level sword fighter had acknowledged my strength. That should be more than enough to prove I was qualified to at least join the guild as a normal member. Besides, at this rate, even if I entered the guild forcibly, it’d only incur their ire, which didn’t help me going forward. I had done my duty toward Palinchron. So I chose the spell for the job.

“I’m going to add a little magic, if you don’t mind. Spellcast: Form.”

“Tch.” But Mr. Vohlzark didn’t flinch. He kept on attacking. “I’ll smash right through your tricksy nonsense!”

As I made the magic bubbles adhere to him, he increased his speed to greater heights and swung his sword. However, the bubbles transmitted the information regarding his sword’s trajectory in more exact detail. There was no way his blade could ever hit me now. As I dodged his blows, I got a precise handle on his habits, allowing me to predict his movements. Using that information, I let his thunderous flurry of giant sword swings graze me lightly on the cheek. A thin bead of blood dripped down.

“Ah, you grazed me,” I said after promptly distancing myself. Palinchron had said that all they had to do was land a single hit.

But Mr. Vohlzark gritted his teeth in frustration, and after heaving a sigh, he replied, “No, don’t count that ‘wound.’ Chalk it up as an unqualified loss for me.”

That was all he offered before unhurriedly leaving the battlefield. I could tell from his demeanor that he had realized I’d sustained the cut on purpose. I had done it that way to safeguard the man’s pride, but I might have only damaged it that much more gravely instead. I wanted him to forgive me, given that for the sake of my future livelihood, I could hardly afford to beat everybody so one-sidedly.

“Vohlzark acknowledged his defeat, so Kanami wins,” declared Palinchron delightedly.

“Palinchron!” I protested. “You said that if I sustained a single wound, it’d be over. So it’s—”

“That bastard! No wonder Palinchron was talking so big!” said one of the members, interrupting me.

The others piped up too. “Oh, this looks fun. I’m tryin’ my hand next!”

“Not before me!”

“The party leaders both lost, huh? How fascinating!”

For some reason, the crowd was getting fired up after the third battle. It could be the case that a lot of them were already the types who didn’t shy away from a fight. But it was more than that. There was an odd glint in their probing eyes.

Palinchron laughed. “They’re members of a guild. Fighting is their livelihood. There’s no way they’d let this end after one little nick! I just said that to rile ’em up.”

“Damn straight!” said one of many who echoed Palinchron’s sentiment. “Ya can’t end it now! I haven’t gotten a go yet!”

“Are you kidding, hon? That’s barely even a flesh wound,” said one woman. “As long as you can still fight, of course we’re going to do battle.”

“Yo, you fellas mind if I go next?”

My face stiffened. These people were chomping at the bit.

“Hold on a sec, ya galoots!” shouted Mr. Vohlzark. “Glenn’s sister! You go first!”

All eyes were immediately trained on the semifer girl. For a second, the grounds were silent. In that time, she gently shook her head.

“No, thank you. There’s no way I could possibly win.”

“Are you serious?” replied Mr. Vohlzark.

A pause. “Yes. I’m serious.”

“I see.” He took a spot and sat down. “Do as you please, people. I’ll be watching.”

Palinchron watched him with a smile. “Looks like we’ve got a party leader’s permission! Now then, shall we resume?!”

With that, the guild members started waiting their turns outside the battlefield.

“Wait, no, I’m fighting everybody?”

I had no choice. I’d be beating all of them while in a cold sweat.

◆◆◆◆◆

In the end, I couldn’t throw any of my duels. Mr. Vohlzark’s sharp eyes were watching the entire time, and if I’d held back too clearly, Palinchron would have had something to say about it. All I could do was use loads of discretion in order to move this along without much fuss.

“All right, folks,” said Palinchron, “that’s a wrap for today. Now then, since none of you were able to beat him, it’s good and settled—Kanami will be the new guildmaster of Epic Seeker!”

I ended up defeating them all without taking almost any damage to speak of, so he declared me guildmaster without reservation.

“Hold on, Palinchron! Gimme another go at him! I feel like I might touch him this time!”

“No can do. It’s already dark out and time’s a finite resource. You’re all dismissed!”

A handful of them interjected, but Palinchron brought the tournament to a close anyway. Afterward, he communicated administrative information to them before the crowd finally broke up. The vast majority came up to me to have a few words before leaving the training grounds.

“Gotta say, Kanami, you really are silly strong,” said one man amicably. “Mind dueling me again tomorrow?”

“Huh? Sure, sir, that’s fine.”

“You’re always so stiff and formal, Kanami. I don’t need ya speakin’ all polite to me.”

“Thanks...gotcha. From now on, I’ll speak casually.”

I sensed no particular dissatisfaction on his part about my becoming guildmaster. Maybe in the eyes of rough-and-tumble fighters or adventurers like him, strength was the deciding factor in whether they resisted somebody standing above them or not.

“Ah, kid,” said one mage with a smile, “teach me some magic later, okay?”

“Uh, okay, ma’am.”

Next, a middle-aged swordfighter slapped me on the shoulder. “Maybe your skills as guildmaster will come in time. Then again, I bet the folks around ya will help ya out, so don’t sweat it.”

I exhaled. “I’ll give it my all.”

Of course, not everyone was so obliging. Some also approached me with stern expressions.

“Listen here, chum, you haven’t earned my approval yet, got it?”

“Ah, yes, of course. I think that’s a perfectly natural reaction.”

“I’m gonna challenge ya another five times, so say your prayers.”

But before he left, the guy flashed me a smile. And here I’d thought I’d finally encountered somebody normal. Nope. Instead, it was the way a little kid reacted after finding a worthy rival.

Ultimately, while a variety of wry comments were made to me, almost no one came up to me to express blatant malice or spite. At the very least, this wasn’t the attitude one might expect them to show somebody who had waltzed right into the top spot of the organization from out of nowhere. I replied to them in turn with my forced smile, the alarming gap between them and normal people clear as day to me.

Once I was done speaking with the many members, the only ones left in the training grounds were Palinchron and the semifer girl, who was staring vacantly up at the dark night sky.

“Isn’t this...you know, weird?” I asked Palinchron right away.

“Things are looking up, huh, Kanami? You just got a huge promotion.”

“The personnel affairs of our organization frighten me,” I replied. “Not only that, but since they’re giving me such a warm welcome, I doubly can’t believe it.”

“Well, this is the one group where this kind of absurdity is tolerated. It’d never fly in any other guild.”

“I did reckon that any guild you’re in couldn’t be a run-of-the-mill organization, but how on earth...”

I still couldn’t believe it. I’d shown them how strong I was throughout the tournament, sure, but even so, what reason did they have to be so accepting? It was a phenomenon that would never occur in my world. Was it just the result of a difference in culture between my world and theirs? But even if their culture didn’t fuss over the little things and put stock solely in strength, their red-carpet welcome was still beyond the norm.

“It’s in the name: Epic Seeker. Our goal as a guild is to search for epics. For tales of derring-do.”

“So already, it’s not a normal guild.”

“Guilds that work under the government first need to decide on a plan of action that’s in service to the state in some way. One might, for example, seek to maintain public order in Laoravia. Another might try to acquire treasure for Laoravia or train promising new talent for the country. The policy of our guild is to find, quote, unquote, ‘heroes’ in service of Laoravia. Of course, thanks to that daft objective, only eccentrics gather under our banner. Then again, another reason for that is the fact that I basically do all the interviews.”

“Yeah, that would pull in lotsa weirdos.”

“The members of the guild may mouth off, but they’re all the kind of wide-eyed dreamer wackos who are eagerly awaiting a swashbuckling, righteous hero type. That, coupled with Laoravia’s belief in meritocracy, means no one’s gonna speak ill of someone like you, who boasts such overwhelming strength. What happened today is this guild’s raison d’être. And it was with an eye for this very day that I gathered the members I did. I pretty much needed it to go decently smoothly.”

He seemed to be taking enjoyment in it. Some part of him was proud, not unlike a kid bragging about a cool toy of theirs. And I’d gotten a similar vibe from the guild members too. For better or worse, this guild’s group was childlike overall.

“Be a hero for us, Kanami. You can make use of this organization. Let’s get your name out there.”

“Is that what you wish for?”

The ever-aloof Palinchron was now showing me a rare serious expression. “Hmm, my ‘wish’? I guess if I had to call it something, I’d say it’s my pastime. I wanna come face-to-face with a hero of legend. And I see one in you. There’s the fact that you’re an outworlder, but there’s also the fact that you have heroic qualities, so I believe in you.”

“You’re expecting too much of me. I don’t even know what I’m supposed to do to be a ‘hero.’”

As far as I was concerned, “heroes” of that sort existed solely within fairy tales. In modern society, just about the only heroic figures people looked up to were sports stars. I didn’t have a clear picture of what Palinchron and the rest meant by it.

“Oh, don’t worry, the preparations have already been made. A big important personage in a big important country crafted some fun plans. And I do think I’ll mimic it. From what I recall, the plan goes a little something like this: After gladly taking the role of guildmaster,” he said in theatrical tones, “Kanami uses his unparalleled strength to break new ground in the Dungeon, extend the Pathway, and inherit the title of strongest diver from Glenn. At a later date, he’ll take first place at the Brawl. After making his name known throughout the continent, he’ll give folks a hand in various locales as a hero as he travels back to Laoravia, returning in triumph. When the time is ripe, he’ll participate in the war in the north, the advent of the great and merciful hero, the living legend, to the front lines lauded by the supreme commanders fighting there. Yeah, that’s the gist of it.”

The plan was preposterous and idiotic. “Um, what? Count me out. Especially the war bit. No way in hell I’m having anything to do with a war!”

“Ha ha. I was mostly joking, laddie. I guess the only bit I’m not joking about was the Dungeon-clearing part. In the Dungeon, you won’t face animosity from anybody, and you’ll be able to get stronger at your own pace. And being strong’s no detriment to you, for your sake and for your sister’s.”

“Well, I do plan on taking on the Dungeon, so that I’ll do.”

This world contained a labyrinthine entity known as the Dungeon. It was the type you saw all the time in video games—the deeper you go, the stronger the enemies. And that conveniently made it well suited to building up one’s strength.

“If you’ve got any energy to spare, I’d like you to extend the Pathway as well. It’d be helping out Laoravia and the guild, among others. If that’s too much, there’s always vanquishing the Guardian of Floor 30. If you rack up glory and results for Epic Seeker, you’ll hear no complaints from me.”

“Sure, if I’ve got the energy. I do want to contribute to Laoravia in some way for taking me and Maria under its guardianship.”

“Also, if you win the Brawl for us, that’d be another nice contribution. Laoravia’s been lagging behind the other four countries for years and years now. Our hero activities across the lands and our supreme commander in the War in the North are some of the things we’re laughed at for.”

“You’d better be joking. I’m happy if I can just protect the little pocket of the world around me. I’d rather die than have to deal with conflicts between nations.”

“Keh heh, is that right? Okay, I got the memo. Then again, everything I told you is nothing more than a plan. As things stand for you now, give learning the ropes of being guildmaster your undivided attention. And regarding the Dungeon, don’t think about extending the Pathway. You can just focus on getting stronger.”

“Yeah. I’m not thrilled about the personnel affairs, but if I’m gonna be doing it, then I’ve gotta do it right and learn how to be a proper guildmaster. Otherwise, I wouldn’t be doing right by its members...”

Palinchron’s expression turned a tad serious. “Right. If you don’t take over soon, it’ll be too late.”

“Too late? Ah, come to think of it, this country called for you to be a commander, right?”

Going by the earnest look on his face, I presumed Palinchron was worried. I had heard that he’d soon have to part from the Dungeon Alliance. He must have wanted to pass the baton to me before he was forced to leave.

“It is what it is. I did as I pleased for a spell, and now they’re calling me back by force. There was more I’d have liked to do in the Alliance, but it can’t be helped.”

Most would view receiving an appointment from their nation as an honor. Palinchron, on the other hand, seemed to hate the idea from the bottom of his heart.

“I see. So, soon enough, I won’t be seeing you anymore, huh?”

“Once I’m gone, have Snow help you out. She’s a long-serving submaster.”

“Long-serving submaster?”

He pointed at the semifer girl who was gazing at the sky in a corner of the grounds. “She’s been serving as a submaster for six years. She’s probably more knowledgeable about Epic Seeker than I am. C’mon, Snow, introduce yourself.”

The young woman came up next to me and offered a hand. A very pretty hand. A feminine, pale, and soft-looking hand.

Epic Seeker’s guildmaster role was unoccupied, effectively consisting of a trio of submasters. Two of those were Palinchron and Mr. Rayle, both of whom were influential adults with power and intelligence, which meant that this girl was on par with them. I gently gripped her hand in mine.

“I’m Snow Walker, a dragonewt. Nice to meet you, Guildmaster Kanami.”

“Er, nice to meet you, Snow...or should I call you Snowy?”

Going by appearances, she looked younger than me, allowing me to refer to her that way. But now that I knew she’d been a submaster for six years, I wasn’t confident that she was as young as she looked.

“We’re probably around the same age,” said Snow. “Caring about such things is a pain, so you can call me whatever you like.”

“Thanks. All right, I’ll go with Snow. And you can call me whatever you like. No need for the polite register.”

“Then I’ll call you Kanami. And I’ll speak casually too.”

It seemed she was indeed as young as she looked, which meant that she’d been a submaster since before she was ten years old.

“Kanami, Snow, I want you two to work together to run Epic Seeker so that the guild will be okay in my and Rayle’s absence.”

“So what you’re saying is, operate the guild, the two of us. You’re honestly going to have us do it? When we’re this young?”

“Great!” she said, smiling happily.

I threw myself onto the bed beside my precious little sister, and she gripped my hand adoringly.

“Your hand’s cold to the touch. It feels nice.”

She relaxed, the tension leaving her body. It was then that I realized she’d been tense and on her toes the entire time I hadn’t been with her. And of course she had. She’d been tossed into another world, lost her eyes, and waited for her brother in the dark... How could her heart find any relief? There was no question that until my touch soothed her nerves, she hadn’t felt any peace of mind, not even for a second.

I resolved to continue sharing a bed with Maria even after I received my room as guildmaster. I’d never leave her side again. I would be there for her. And if I wasn’t wrong, I’d made a promise to that effect in the past...

As I tried to remember what exactly I’d promised, I closed my eyes and gave my body over to the land of sleep. I had the peace of mind that falling asleep beside family offered. And yet that nagging unease was still present. Now that we were together, brother and sister, I was supposed to be happy. There was something I couldn’t put my finger on.

I shook my head a little and banished the thoughts from my mind. Let’s just get some shut-eye for now. First things first; I’ve gotta carve out a secure place for us in this world.

I was going to earn money to cover Maria’s medical expenses while consolidating my standing in Laoravia. And to accomplish that, I’d need to shed blood, sweat, and tears starting the next day. I didn’t have the time to sit and worry.

I kept repeating that in my head, gripping Maria’s hand tight as I fell asleep.

Chapter 2: For You Who’ll See No Recompense

Early the next morning, Snow came to wake me up. Seeing us siblings sleeping in the same bed, she smiled. It was a mysterious little smile. Was she shocked? Envious? Reminiscing? All three at once? In any case, that might have been the first time I’d ever seen her smile.

After she was done bidding Maria a good morning, she wasted no time taking me out of there. It seemed as though she would tell me all about my guild work quite early in the day.

She took me to the office prepared for the guildmaster, where she full-on drummed into me the fundamentals of the organization. The morning of day one was spent solely on boning up; my work as guildmaster began in earnest, starting around noon.

Ten or so members gathered at the training grounds to check on the plans for the day. At first, Palinchron took the wheel, but then it fell to me to issue the orders regarding the Epic Seeker’s business that day. I, of course, tried to decline, but Palinchron said that if I did it with Snow’s help, it’d be a piece of cake. Then he immediately left, leaving the guildmaster (i.e., me), my submaster Snow, and the assembled guild members.

Snow and I tried to think of the most efficient way to run the guild using the cards we’d been dealt. Otherwise, we wouldn’t be doing right by the members in attendance. And then, after a lot of thought, we hit upon a solution.

◆◆◆◆◆

A mountain of papers, reports, applications, and the like towered in front of me. My quill was dancing frenetically across the documents. I affirmed the flow of guild resources, improved the management of funds, and reviewed the stationing of our personnel. And to do that, I updated the required papers in turn.

While I was at my desk doing all this paperwork, I simultaneously gave out instructions for the fieldwork. My overpowered, downright unfair dimensional magic allowed me to grasp the situation out in the field even while I was at our home base. Moreover, at my current level, my INT stat was now among the highest of all humanity, enabling me to do both tasks at the same time.

“Kanami, the orders for Tayly’s party,” muttered Snow quietly. She was right beside me, providing support.

In response, I organized the information that Dimension had picked up for me, zeroing in on the real-time feed I was getting of Ms. Tayly’s party chasing after a robber several kilometers to HQ’s north-northeast.

“Yep, I see ’em. Let’s see...Ms. Tayly should turn at the next left and stand by at the third bend in the road. I’d appreciate it if the other members keep pursuing the target. It’ll take twenty—no, seventeen seconds for the target to run right into Ms. Tayly. Tell her to intercept the robber with her magic but to be careful too. Then the target’ll be outflanked in a pincer attack.”

“Okay. I’ll tell them.” Snow disinterestedly spoke into the magic gem in her hand, relaying what I’d said. Through the gem, she was now in contact with Ms. Tayly and her party, who were kilometers away from us. My hand didn’t stop writing, continuing to put the paperwork in order even as I listened to verify the accuracy of her message to them. Needless to say, I also checked to see if the party had successfully captured the robber, never pausing from doing the paperwork in the meantime.

Dimension informed me of what was happening. The robber was taken aback when they found Ms. Tayly standing right in front of them, and the others came to cut off any avenue of escape before summarily arresting the offender.

“How’d it go?” asked Snow.

“Went without a hitch. The target was kept in place by Ms. Tayly’s magic, and then the members had them surrounded. Capture complete. With that, Ms. Tayly’s party is done with their commission. It ended faster than I thought.”

“Of course it did. There’s no way the robber had any idea there could be somebody who had a grasp of the entire town.”

“But isn’t Palinchron able to do something similar?”

“If you’re talking about Palinchron’s Spellrite, you’re wrong. It’s hampered by all sorts of harsh restrictions. Besides, it’s not as accurate as your magic is. It can’t do all this.”

“I see.”

I’d heard that Palinchron was one of the most prominent users of detection magic on the continent, but it seemed that my dimensional magic was more precise and accurate than his abilities allowed for.

“I won’t mince words,” said Snow, “this is crazy. Palinchron wanted us to do this?”

“Looks like it. Apparently, after hearing about what you and I can do, he came up with this combo. I’m glad it went well. Through this, I can do something guildmastery in form, if not in substance.”

“No, I’d say this makes you many times more competent than your average guildmaster. I have to hand it to you, Master...”

“Snow, please stop calling me that. I dunno why, but being called that by a girl like you gets to me. Could you call me by my name instead?”

A pause. “Uh-huh. Roger that.”

When she saw that it really did bother me, she nodded. On the whole, she was rather meek and pliable. She could even be called weak-willed.

“Ah, another robber,” I said. Dimension caught a crime in progress at the edge of its area of effect.

Another pause (as was common with her). “Urgh. Again?”

“Mr. Vohlzark and his people are nearby, so tell them to handle it. Let’s score some brownie points.”

“That sounds like work.”

“C’mon, Snow, we may be on the clock, but we’ve gotta catch the robber for the sake of the people who call Laoravia home too.”

“Hmm. Look, if it’s a pain, it’s a pain. And it’s not something anybody’s commissioned the guild for, so...”

While she was rather meek, she was also extremely work-shy. She didn’t like putting her all into anything, she hated getting tired, and she slacked off whenever possible—to a downright absurd extent.

“A pain? All you have to do is repeat what I said, don’t you?”

“I thought a job where all I have to do is parrot stuff would be easy street, but it’s surprisingly tiresome.”

“Hey, don’t forget that I’m the one doing all the filing that you’re supposed to be doing. I’m happy to stop helping you, you know?”

“You’re killing me here.”

“Just tell them already.”

Leveraging the fact that I was shouldering some of her work, I got Snow to start speaking into her gem, albeit with a look of resignation. Mr. Vohlzark was walking through town when he heard her message, and he replied.

I took Dimension and turned it into Layered Dimension, focusing it on the immediate area around him so that I could pick up on the movements of his lips and the vibrations of his voice. From what he was saying, he had the energy to take down the brigand. Looking at their stats, I knew I had nothing to worry about. The thief was low-level and Mr. Vohlzark had enough HP. A direct confrontation shouldn’t be a problem.

“Good, he said he’ll do it. Now then, tell him to head toward the market at Lot 67. When he’s close enough, I’ll give him more detailed navigation. Incidentally, the target’s Level 5 and there’s nothing to take note of, so ask him to arrest the brigand head-on.”

“I’ll tell him.” She repeated my instructions.

Having received my orders through the magic gem, the hulk of a man zipped toward the criminal, getting closer and closer. I kept track of the movements of both pursuer and target through Dimension, the gap between them closing like two chess pieces on the game board. Before long, the two bumped into each other and the brigand was apprehended. It couldn’t have been clearer who was stronger between them, and the battle ended in a flash. Mr. Vohlzark took the rogue to the store they had victimized, and the proprietor burst into tears of joy at the return of the stolen goods. Judging by those tears, if the items had remained stolen, the damage to the shopkeeper’s livelihood might have been grave. I was happy to have prevented such a tragedy.

Then the robber was taken to a government-run public safety office, and that was the end of it. The whole thing had taken a matter of minutes, but we’d rescued yet another citizen of Laoravia.

“Phew... the shopkeeper’s expressing his joy...”

“Is he now.”

It seemed Snow wasn’t able to identify with my relief. She was looking up at the sky through the window, indifference written on her face. Whenever she didn’t have anything to do, she had a habit of basking in the sun like that.

“If you’re free, I’d like you to help me with the paperwork and such.”

“It’s okay. Thanks to you, enough of it’s already been done that I won’t get yelled at.”

“Ah, okay, so that’s your standard for what’s good enough.”

“I’m not like you. I don’t like doing everything that’s in my power to the best of my ability.”

Over the course of the day, I’d gotten a grasp of Snow’s personality. She was of the opinion that she wasn’t compatible with me as guildmaster, and it wasn’t as though I didn’t understand where she was coming from. Back in my world and when I had gone to school, I’d had exactly the same stance as her. Being in this world was entirely to blame for my working so hard now. If not for how tough it was to get by in this environment, chances were high I’d be behaving the same way.

“I mean, sure, but if you aren’t there to watch me, I won’t be able to rest easy. After all, I’m a newbie, and there’s always the possibility I’m operating under the wrong assumptions.”

“That’s Palinchron’s fault for allocating us like this. We should have resigned ourselves the moment an outsider started doing the filing.”

“That’s true. Giving a newbie all these important documents to sort through on his first day is all kinds of crazy.”

“Exactly. And as such, I can’t be blamed. And since I can’t be blamed, I won’t put in any more effort than I am now.”

“Ah, gotcha.”

I didn’t chide her. I merely faced Paperwork Mountain again in silence. And that was because simply by communicating to people through her magic gems, she was doing the work of dozens.

The colors outside the window were getting a touch of red as the sun started descending. The paperwork I’d been doing since noon was just about over with too, and the guild parties that were scattered about had completed their respective tasks. I reckoned I had done a decent job for my first day as guildmaster. I mustered the resolve to finish up the remaining paperwork and buckled down, but just as I was about to be done with it at last, I detected somebody entering the Epic Seeker headquarters.

Now that the sun was setting, almost all of the members had gone home for the day, Ms. Tayly among them. I was holding her report on the mission she had cleared earlier.

After realizing that someone had started conversing with Palinchron over by the entranceway, I left Snow behind and headed toward the two. I wanted to report to them the fruits of the day’s labor and, if possible, get their appraisals of me straight from the horse’s mouth.

I walked through the interior of Epic Seeker’s home base, arriving at a place where I could hear Palinchron and Ms. Tayly talk.

“So whaddya think? Kanami’s outstanding as guildmaster, ain’t he?”

“He is. More so than even you. We received accurate info at scary fast speeds. He’s basically completely negated the need for the intel-gathering process. Thanks to that, we wrapped up the commission that had a seven-day deadline in mere hours. It almost feels like cheating.”

“If the guys over in the suzerain land knew about either Kanami or Snow, they’d do anything to get their hands on such shining talents. You’ve seen how well their skills combine. Isn’t that only natural?”

“It’s only natural, he says... But they still lack experience. If they didn’t have connections, few would know of them.”

“What they lack in connections and experience, the guild members can make up for with their own. Those two are straight-edged. They’ll listen to what their elders have to say. And don’t worry about widening their circles; I’m already teaching them lots.”

“You’re putting an awful lot of effort into his success. I see you’re serious with regard to Kanami. I’ve never seen you this antsy, Palinchron.”

“Heh heh, if I look antsy, I’ve still got a ways to go. Hey, I just wanna go to the suzerain land worry-free, that’s all.”

It was a bad habit of mine. Whenever Dimensions was active, I turned into an eavesdropper without even meaning to. I walked over to the two at a quick pace, partly to avoid eavesdropping more than I already had.

“Palinchron, I’ve basically finished all the paperwork-related stuff.”

“Oh hey, if it ain’t Kanami. All right, so how much of it is left?”

“How much is left? Er, well, basically nothing...”

Apart from the slight amount I’d left for Snow’s sake, I’d completed absolutely all of the documents I’d been handed.

Palinchron looked flabbergasted. “Nothing? Did you see the size of that heap of papers?”

“Yep, and I did it all. You told me that doing it was the guildmaster’s job, didn’t you? So I got it all over with today.”

“Wait, hold on. Something’s off! There’s no way you could finish it all that easily! Sure, there were documents you just had to give a look-see, but there were also others that involved super tedious income and expenditure calculations!”

It was true; there were such documents. But I was already done knocking the numbers around—the guild logistics and its attendant costs, the personnel expenses for everyone, the details of balancing earnings and expenditures, etc.

“Maybe it’s because the math I’m using is different? Bookkeeping and math are both strong suits of mine.”

“You... You’re not joking?”

“Plus, using Layered Dimension, I can really play nasty and look at multiple documents at the same time. Also, now that I’ve leveled up, I’ve got the feeling that I’m able to think about multiple things at the same time too.”

I’d recently started to notice how clearly my brain power had increased compared to when I was back on Earth. I wasn’t just talking about the speed of my thoughts either. The very way my thinking worked had changed. One facet of that change was the segmentation of my thought streams, allowing me to multitask.

“Could it be that Snow put her all into helping you with it?”

“Er, not really. I’d say she barely helped me with it at all.”

In fact, I’d done Snow’s share of the work for her. She’d earnestly informed me about all sorts of stuff that morning, but only so she could foist everything on me. She’d been loafing around since noon.

“It’s true, that’s insanely fast even if Snow gave you a hand with it... Sure, you may have leveled up, but that shouldn’t be reason enough for you to be able to pull that off... On the other hand, I guess it’s maybe not impossible, given the special traits of your magic energy? Or maybe it’s a quality of dimensional magic...or maybe it’s the price you paid?”

“In any case, I’m done. I can call it a day now, right?”

“Ah, yeah, sorry. In fact, considering all the work you did today, you can call it a week.”

“What? That was seven days’ worth?” I asked, surprised.

At first, I’d been taken aback by the quantity of papers, but I’d tackled it thinking it was a reasonable amount of material for one day at a mid-size organization. The fact that it was actually a week’s worth of work felt underwhelming.

“Palinchron,” said Ms. Tayly, “maybe it’s not magic or what have you. Maybe it’s Kanami himself who’s a bit...peculiar?”

“Don’t say it out loud; I’m stunned too.”

The two of them looked at me like I had two heads. I smiled wryly. “Uh, so, I guess I should just focus on helping out the members then?”

“Actually, it looks like the jobs assigned for the week are finished for the most part too. Tayly’s given us her report, and with that, everyone’s quests have been accomplished...thanks to your assistance, Kanami.”

“Uh...isn’t that too little work?” I asked honestly. I didn’t know what I was going to do the next day.

“It’s true that the work I gave you is on the low side; it’s your first week as guildmaster, after all. But still...it wasn’t that little work. If anything, it was the average amount for a guild.”

“It... It was?”

I myself was starting to notice just how consequential this was—the sheer grandness of my capabilities and the sheer scope of my ability to command whenever I had Snow’s magic to help me. It seemed it gave rise to a state of affairs so out of the ordinary that it sped up the guild’s workings by a factor of seven.

Palinchron looked sullen. “I’ll talk it over with Laoravia and bring you more work to do next week. Until then, go ahead and clear some more of the Dungeon. That’ll contribute to the guild too, so far as it goes.”

“Roger that,” I said, nodding.

“What about us, Palinchron?” said Ms. Tayly.

“Just like always, you can use your spare time any way you like. You can take on quests through public organizations, and you can go wherever you want with your party.”

“Got it.”

From the look of it, I’d gotten too enthusiastic with it being my first day on the job, and now nobody in Epic Seeker had any work to do. Once we were done discussing the policy going forward, we decided to disperse, and I made my way to the training grounds, where the guild members who had nothing planned were hanging out. I’d gone there to apologize for being such an eager beaver, but they told me there was no need to say sorry. Almost all of them seemed to think there was nothing better than wrapping up their work early. Far from criticizing me, more people than not praised me for the high precision of my orders.

I spent my time there deepening my bond with the guild members. With some, I accepted requests for rematches. With others, we taught each other about magic. In doing so, I closed the distance between me and them, a little at a time.

When night came, I bade Snow goodnight, ate dinner with Maria, and shared a bed with her again. And that was how my first day as guildmaster ended. I couldn’t have hoped for a smoother start.

◆◆◆◆◆

On my second day of guild life, without any work to do (on account of my being too revved up the day prior), I found myself standing before the entrance to the Dungeon.

Snow had said she would “spend the day sky-gazing,” so I’d forced her to accompany me. Otherwise, she would have just been screwing around doing nothing. Besides, Palinchron had told us to work as a unit.

“All right, it’s time to Dungeon dive.”

“Ugh, what a hassle.”

“Snow, this is another of the guild’s tasks. Palinchron told me to either extend the Pathway or take down a Guardian.”

“Yeah, but he didn’t give you a deadline. Why don’t we just phone it in?”

“I wouldn’t go so far as to say ‘phone it in,’ but I don’t intend to go all out either. For the most part, I plan to look for treasure while hunting easy monsters here and there.”

“Hmm. There’s a chance that monsters you consider easy enemies are ones I view as a pain.”

“You’re good, Snow. I mean it. You can just phone it in. I’m gonna do most everything myself. All you have to do is watch from behind.”

As usual, I convinced her not to flake out on me. To be honest, I didn’t expect all that much from a lazy bones like her, but she did harbor a minimum sense of responsibility for me, so if I was in danger, she’d most likely step in. She was my insurance in case the shit hit the fan, so to speak.

“Oh? I’m just watching? That’s good. I’m happy with that.”

“Okay, great. Now then, let’s go in.”

【PARTY】

Snow Walker has joined.

I entered the Dungeon alongside Snow as the notification hit my eyes.

There we were, in the damp, dark corridors. That musty blood smell, those paths with the characteristic points of luminescence... Part of me was feeling nostalgic. I was back in the Dungeon. For some reason, all it had taken was that fire to make me miss the place terribly.

“Kanami, something wrong?”

I’d halted in my tracks at some point. “No, it’s nothing. Let’s go.”

“Okay.”

I shook off that emotion that was useless for Dungeon diving and continued down the hallway. In the past, I’d... I’d reached Floor 24. I remembered.

Exploring Floor 24 had proven it was a harsh floor, so I had chosen to level grind at Floor 19 instead. That was my latest memory. But the memory was like an old, blurry, black-and-white photo. There were dark spots in all the most pivotal parts, so I was having trouble excavating the memory. Maybe the vagueness of my memories from around that point in time was due to the shock of the fire.

But I couldn’t complain. I pulled myself together and determined a plan of action for our dive. My companion was Level 16, and her stats weren’t much different from mine. That being said, in terms of endurance, she probably had me beat by a few ranks. She also had a rich selection of magic she’d acquired, and her well was fathomless.

【STATUS】

NAME: Snow Walker

HP: 530/533

MP: 229/240

CLASS: Scout

LEVEL 16

STR 10.22

VIT 10.02

DEX 5.24

AGI 5.43

INT 7.92

MAG 10.86

APT 2.62

INNATE SKILLS: Draconic Protection 1.09, Optimal Moves 1.89, Ancient Magic 2.04

Mind’s Eye 1.07, Blood Magic 1.00

ACQUIRED SKILLS: None

Our objective for the day was to grind at Level 19 or thereabouts, then reestablish the Connection portal at Floor 20. Thanks to the fire, the registration of all of my Connection doors had been dispelled, forcing me to go in from Level 1 again. It was a pain, but it couldn’t be helped. I figured I’d zip straight to Floor 20.

Since the Pathway reached all the way to Floor 23, the way there was a breeze. Furthermore, for divers on our level, the single-digit floors presented no threats. After a few hours of walking, we were able to reach Floor 10 without a hitch.

When we entered Floor 10, we were taken aback by its dreariness.

“Wait, huh? There’s nothing here.”

“Just a little while ago, there was a sea of fire in here. Looks like it’s true—the Guardian of Floor 10 really is dead.”

“Really? If that’s true, that’s amazing. It’d take a bona fide hero to take down a Guardian, wouldn’t it? I wonder what the person who did it is like?”

I didn’t know much, but even I knew that the entities called Guardians were terribly strong. They were boss monsters that not even parties composed of the strongest divers could beat. They were the stuff of legends for all who ventured into the Dungeon.

“Amazing is right, though I’m pretty sure it must’ve been you who did it.”

“Huh? Me? Why?”

“Never mind. I’m just talking to myself.”

“You say that, but you said it so that I could hear, didn’t you?”

“I can’t be assed to say any more. Let’s keep going.”

I sighed, nodding reluctantly. “All right, fine.”

Whenever Snow said a topic of conversation was a pain, there could be no continuing it. That had been driven home for me the day prior while we were working together. As such, I didn’t press her. Whatever she was talking about was probably connected to what she’d said about my memories on the day we met. It wasn’t something I wanted to hear over and over.

We silently walked across the now-barren Floor 10. No vestige of the blazing fire that once characterized the room was anywhere to be seen. Likely because of that jump between then and now, it felt all the more hollow. It was so empty, it practically screamed that those majestic and pompous flames would never return. It had nothing to do with me and yet...it felt so melancholic for some reason.

That strange emotion enveloped me as I set up a magic gateway in a corner of the room.

“Spellcast: Connection.”

I took a camo-cloth from my inventory and shrouded the door with it so that it wouldn’t stand out.

“This is dimensional magic?”

“Yeah. Now I’ll be able to come and go from my office at the guild.”

“But if you leave it like this, other divers will use it, no?”

“Ugh, you’re right. Let’s do it this way. Spellcast: Ice.”

I used ice magic to lightly freeze the portal. The Connection doorway was brittle and crumbled easily. Normally, one wouldn’t be able to freeze it solid, but as I was the one who had cast the spell, I had a flawless grasp of its structure, so I was able to freeze it without destroying it.

Because I had woven the spell while visualizing something different from the typical Ice, it behooved me to give it a new name: Ice Lock.

“You froze it?” asked Snow.

“If someone tries to melt the ice, the door will break. The only one who can melt it and still be able to use it is me, since I was the one who cast both spells. Guess I’ll name this one Ice Lock.”

“Weird name. But I suppose it’s better than nothing?”

“Either way, putting a door on Floor 10 isn’t particularly useful. Let’s set one up on Floor 20 good and quick. Your average diver can’t reach Floor 20, so I can rest easier if that’s where the portal is.”

“Oof. Can’t we just call it a day here?”

“Nope. Let’s go, Snow.”

“Urgh.”

With that, we ventured farther into the Dungeon.

◆◆◆◆◆

We were walking down the Pathway on Floor 14, on our way to Floor 20, when it happened.

“The hell is that?”

I spotted a monster traveling at high-speed within Dimension’s range, stopping us in our tracks. It moved at velocities that outstripped the monsters of Floor 14. Figuring it must be a formidable one, I promptly used Analyze from afar.

【MONSTER】Line Skitter: Rank 1

Contrary to my expectations, it was weirdly low-level. Now it was out of place on Floor 14 in a whole different way. It looked like a small mouse that was glowing blue. But it was no normal glow.

Curious, I decided to chase after it. Snow, who stood behind me, looked like she could fall asleep at any moment. I let her be and walked in the direction of the Line Skitter without her. However, since it was running around without settling in a specific area, getting closer to it was no mean feat. The more I gave chase, though, the more I came to understand the rules and patterns governing its running path. I now knew for sure that no amount of walking would ever lead to an encounter with it. Left with no other choice, I made Snow wait for me on the Pathway so that I could go out on the hunt. Snow couldn’t keep up with my all-out running speed—a peculiarity born of our stats. My stats specialized in speed, while hers were focused on endurance.

After warning her not to fall asleep on the Pathway, I blasted off in pursuit of the Line Skitter. Predicting which corridors it would dart down, I gradually closed the distance by repeatedly heading it off. After a few minutes of that, I succeeded in coming face-to-face with the fleet-footed creature. I then retrieved my sword from my inventory and slashed at it to see what would happen. The second I did, the Line Skitter picked up its pace.

“What the?!”

That one swing was the only one I got. The thing easily dodged it and zipped right past me, disappearing down the shadowy corridor. Initially, I tried to chase after it, but then I remembered it was speedy enough to evade my sword and I stopped in my tracks. In all likelihood, its top speed outstripped my own. There was no doubt about it now—this was a special miniboss-type creature. A “bonus monster,” if you would. At least, that was the feeling I got.

Realizing that simply chasing after it would yield no results, I was forced to put the sword back in my inventory. This was starting to get exciting.

I searched my arsenal of spells and my inventory for a path to victory. The spell that usually made me the most confident, Wintermension, was a no-go for this. That spell was for intercepting enemies that were coming at me. It did very little to impede an enemy that was fleeing from me. The same went for Blizzardmension. While it did apply a deceleration effect, it’d be exceedingly difficult to get the Line Skitter within its range. Sure, I could spend more magic energy to enlarge its area of effect, but it’d probably be a long shot regardless. I also had Ice Arrow for a long-range attack, but given how fast the target was, I wasn’t confident I could hit it, even with the help of Dimension: Calculash. As such, my one remaining option was a spell that was more of a trap.

I took some water out of my inventory and created a large pool of water in the path I knew the Line Skitter would cross. Then I placed one pocket of Snowmension over it. Needless to say, I didn’t make it burst just yet. Since the creature raced across the floor, the chances were high it would fall for the trap. And since it was only Rank 1, I figured even a trap this cheap and fast might get the job done.

After making five such puddles, I ascertained the Line Skitter’s position and chased after it like I had before; I was corralling it toward the group of traps I’d laid. I had to be as fast as possible. The crux of the water trap lay in Snowmension. If a separate monster caused Snowmension to activate, the trap would go to waste.

As I chased the thing around and around, it finally stepped inside the area with the trap. I devoted my full attention to getting the timing for activating the trap exactly right. And the instant that the Line Skitter stepped in the water, I made Snowmension burst open. The cold air popped out of its sphere, freezing the water in a flash—and of course, the monster’s legs with it.

I used Dimension to confirm that I’d captured my prey before hurrying over to it. I saw it there, squeaking as it struggled to extricate itself from the ice. It looked as though this monster was all speed and no power. My heart panged for it slightly, but I reminded myself repeatedly that this was just the law of the jungle and sliced the Line Skitter’s body with my blade.

【TITLE UNLOCKED: Brightline Sprint】

+0.05 to AGI.

Then I used Analyze on the magic gem drop.

【CRESCENT PECTOLAZRI】

An aggregation of magic energy that emits a flash of light.

A rare drop from the cursed monster of unmatched speed.

That description only underlined the fact that it was a rare gem. It was a relief to know that the reward was commensurate with the effort I expended. Having accomplished what I’d set out to do, I made my way back to where Snow was—to find her with her eyes closed on the edge of the Pathway...despite how pointedly I’d cautioned her. She wasn’t snoring, which was the least one might expect, but it still chagrined me.

“Snow, I told you not to fall asleep.”

“Mrhmm. Huh, wha? Oh, I’m awake, I’m awake.”

“Oh yeah? Even though you were slow on the uptake just now?”

“Don’t worry about it. Never mind that—did you kill the thing you saw?” she asked, trying to change the subject. She was such a dyed-in-the-wool lazybones that it was clearly no use admonishing her.

“Yep, I caught it in a trap. Look at what it dropped.”

“Oh, wow. This thing’s so rare that in any given year, it’s not guaranteed that even one will make the rounds in the whole of the Dungeon Alliance. It’s a Crescent Pectolazri, if I’m not wrong?”

“Yeah, you’re right. I worked my ass off for it.”

“It’s not a given that you’ll get a drop upon killing one of those things. That’s why they’re so few and far between. Nice that it did drop for you, huh, Kanami?”

“Is that right? Guess luck was on my side!”

And I’d been all the luckier considering how coincidental it was that I’d detected the Line Skitter through Dimension to begin with.

“All righty, now that you’ve grabbed yourself a goodie, what say we get a move on?” she said, a faux show of enthusiasm.

It couldn’t have been more obvious that she just didn’t want to get told off again after she’d caught those Zs on the Pathway earlier.

I sighed. “Yeah, you’re right. Let’s keep going.”

If I’d had my way, I’d have lectured her for a good hour or so. It wasn’t unheard of for Dungeon monsters to brave the Pathway, there was always a chance she’d get attacked by other divers, and there were any number of situations she might not see coming. But Snow being the way she was, it was highly likely it would all fall on deaf ears. I pondered ways to rectify her personality as we walked down the corridor. And so, after a spot of good fortune, we pressed farther into the Dungeon.

◆◆◆◆◆

I’d told Snow that she didn’t have to do any fighting, but that promise went out the window at around the halfway point of Floor 19. Unforeseen situations were unavoidable in the Dungeon, and now that we were surrounded by monsters, even Snow had no choice but to engage.

We were up against Carmine Minotaurs, which were denizens of Floor 19, but Snow dispatched them with ease. Thanks to the boosts granted to her as a member of the dragonewt race, she was even stronger than her STR stat let on, and she borrowed two large weapons that were larger than her from me, which she brandished in battle. She was so rough with them, however, that she was tearing through the weapons like candy. All the same, her overwhelming display of strength convinced me that I didn’t need to worry about her. She was definitely a submaster of a guild under the control of a nation’s government for a reason.

Since I no longer had to worry about my comrade behind me, our Dungeon diving got even faster. We progressed to Floor 20, which was another drab, lifeless space in the vein of Floor 10. I wasted no time setting up a Connection gateway in a corner of the room, just like I’d done on the tenth floor. With that, we could always take a shortcut to the twentieth.

“All right, good. We’ve finished marking Floor 20 now too. Mission accomplished.”

“Good, let’s go back, then. Time to call it a day and rock on home!”

“We’re not calling it a day, but we can head back. I’m thinking I might get someone in Epic Seeker to cast a heal spell.”

“A heal spell? You mean you wanna work me even more?”

“Like you’re working that much now. Let’s get moving.”

Through Connection, we traveled to the office at Epic Seeker HQ. Using Dimension, I searched for a member who could cast a healing spell. Since I’d demolished all the work for the week the day prior, it was easy to find someone with time on their hands.

I called out to a member with a command of holy magic and had them heal my wounds. Not that I’d struggled very much; they were all just scratches to begin with. The mage who healed me grinned as they did so, which creeped me out. I asked them why, and they replied that healing the wounds of the strong was what made them get out of bed in the morning. As might be expected of an Epic Seeker healer, they clearly had some screws loose.

After confirming that Snow and I had recovered our HP, I made to dive right back into the Dungeon, but Snow had something to say about it.

“Please, I need a break.”

“No can do. We’re in perfect shape again. There’s no reason not to go.”

“If we don’t take any breaks, it’ll take a mental toll on us. Oh, I know! Take out the Crescent Pectolazri.”

I retrieved it from my inventory and showed it to her. “What do you need with this thing?”

“Let’s take it to our blacksmith. If it’s workable, we can ask them to make it into a new weapon for you. With a gem this rare, I figure it’ll turn out interesting.”

“Oh, does Epic Seeker have a resident blacksmith? That does sound intriguing.”

I could agree with the need to upgrade our weapons. I’d worn out some swords, and Snow had been a tornado of wear and tear on the weapons. At first, I’d thought relying on mass-produced stuff would be fine, but in the long run, I might need some more expensive, one-of-a-kind items with greater staying power.

“All right, let’s go,” said Snow. “I’ll have them make all sorts of stuff. And I’ll be right there watching.”

“Right there sleeping, more like,” I said with a strained smile.

And so we headed for the atelier located at the edge of Epic Seeker HQ.

◆◆◆◆◆

“Er...hello, coming through,” I said, entering the atelier, from which black smoke was rising.

The building looked big from the outside, but the inside was smaller than I expected. Work tools littered the space, making it quite cramped, and there were several timeworn workbenches and furnaces installed. It was sweltering hot in the room, and the air quality was poor, what with all the soot and dust. This wasn’t a place where one wished to stick around for very long.

“Huh? Whazzat?” asked a long-haired man who was gazing at a sword in the back of the workroom. “A customer, is that it? Er, what business have you?”

“I came bringing various magic gems. Could you make something for me?”

“Ah, yes, yes, I see. Yes, that’s fine. Ain’t got anything to do anyway.”

He put down the sword he’d been looking at and approached me while brushing up his long locks. With his face now bared, I was taken aback by the sheer number of scars carved into it. One of his eyes was permanently shut, and both his ears had been cut off. There were also burn scars all over his face. It was painful just looking at it.

“Uh, it’s a...it’s a pleasure to meet you.”

“Ack, sorry, did I startle ya? I don’t blame ya. First time can be a doozy—wait, hold on, you’re our guildmaster, ain’t ya? Ya didn’t have to waste your time coming to this filthy hole. Ya coulda called me and I’d have come, ya know.”

“That’s all right, I’m the one with business, so it’s only fair I be the one to make the trip. And it’s not as though I’m here to order you as your guildmaster. I came here for personal reasons, just as a guy named Kanami. Your name’s, er...Mr. Alibers?”

“Alibers Riverth. You remembered! Even though I didn’t duel ya during that round-robin.”

“I memorized everyone’s names like my life depended on it.”

We introduced ourselves as we shook hands. I had a little look at Mr. Alibers’s skills.

【SKILLS】

INNATE SKILLS: Holy Magic 1.34

ACQUIRED SKILLS: Elemental Magic 0.23, Smithing 0.89, Swordplay 0.07

His Smithing skill wasn’t terribly high. If anything, he was more blessed in the combat department. He wasn’t very high-level, yet his magic power was top-notch. If somebody had told me he was a Dungeon-diving mage and not a blacksmith, I’d have believed them. The chances were high that he had indeed been a diver in the past but had switched to being a blacksmith after sustaining his injuries, causing a drop in his combat-relevant skills over time.

“Now then, Master, what sortsa stuff’d ya bring me today?”

“I brought a gem that Snow told me is rare.”

I fetched the gem from my inventory. And while I was at it, I showed him all the stuff I thought might be rare from among the drops I’d accumulated. At the assortment of magic gems laid out on the workbench, Mr. Alibers got a gleam in his eye.

“Well, I’ll be! You’ve got stuff ya seldom ever see, even in government money-changers’ shops.”

“I’ve been accumulating a stockpile of them this whole time. Would you be able to use one or more of these to make me a sturdy, durable weapon?”

“You bet I can. With this much to work with, I can make basically anything.”

“If you could, please; thank you. It’s been a pain because my weapons keep breaking on me.”

“I don’t wanna imagine what monsters your weapons are breaking against. I do repair broken weapons as well, ya know? If ya bring ’em to me, I might able to make use o’ them.”

“Really, sir?”

“Most o’ the time, though, it’s cheaper to buy new than to repair.”

“Hmm. I’ll take them out for you.”

Overjoyed that I could get weapons repaired someplace so close by, I fetched my damaged weapons from my inventory. I did so in full view of Mr. Alibers, as I had no intention of hiding my inventory ability from the people I’d be collaborating with. And since he expressed surprise, I gave him a light explanation.

As I was taking out various items, I found a broken sword I had no recollection of. The edge of the blade was warped. The sword looked old, and the blade looked as though it had melted from being stuck into magma.

【TREASURED BLADE OF THE ARRACE CLAN - DAMAGED】

Attack Power 1

It essentially had the same attack power as swinging an iron rod. It did, however, contain the word “treasured” in its name. If one were to go off the name alone, it would seem like a fine sword indeed.

I couldn’t really remember how I’d got my hands on that one. Not that it was uncommon for me to shove valuables left behind in the Dungeon into my inventory. I’d probably picked it up during a dive. I didn’t give it too much thought; I just put the damaged sword on the table for Mr. Alibers.

“I think that’s all of them.”

“Well, that is a lot.”

“Ha ha, sorry about that.”

“Now then, let me have a look-see.”

I decided to survey the weapons alongside Mr. Alibers. If I came to understand what made a weapon repairable or not, it would come in handy for future Dungeon dives. Snow, meanwhile, was sitting on the floor in a corner of the room, grasping her knees, and she was beginning to nod off.

“From what I can see, out of the weapons here, the swords are in the best shape. If they’re sharpened, they can more or less see action again. But I’m thinking these huge weapons are a lost cause. The bases are warped and the blades’re battered. Best bet’s to melt ’em down and turn ’em into materials.”

“I see.”

It seemed that the weapons Snow had used were in particularly bad shape.

“Which leaves us with...hmm, huh? Could this one be...” Mr. Alibers took the Treasured Blade of the Arrace Clan in his hand.

“Is something the matter?”

“No, it’s just this one was forged by a skilled artisan. It’s made o’ rare ore, so the maker’s signature oughta be engraved on it, but...it’s in such terrible condition that I can’t see one.”

“Uh, I think it had the word ‘Arrace’ on it before,” I said, disclosing the information my menu-sight told me in the hopes that it would help him repair it.

“Arrace? Ya mean those Arraces? But I feel like that’s different from the signature...”

“What does Arrace mean?”

“What? Well, I mean, I’m guessing it’s Arrace, as in the big noble clan. They churn out droves o’ outstanding swordfighters, and it’s the noble house with that famous Blademaster, Sir Fenrir Arrace, in it.”

“Wow. That’s crazy.”

As he answered my question, he never took his eye off the blade. Clearly, he had a keen interest in the curious sight of this high-quality sword.

“Hrmm. Unfortunately, I ain’t good enough to repair this. The ore’s too special.”

“In that case, you can just melt it down into raw materials.” To me, it was only a sword I had found on the road. Yet the moment I said that, a chill ran down my spine for some reason. I wondered why.

“No, you oughta keep it with ya. It may be impossible for me, but there’s still hope if ya visit a blacksmith in Whoseyards.”

“Huh. There is?”

It wasn’t as though I had any particular attachment to the blade. I would’ve been fine if he’d turned it into materials, but in his eyes, that would have been a waste.

“The other thing that jumped out at me is this gem here. A Crescent Pectolazri, if I recall. If ya sell it, you could spend the next three years high on the hog. Ya sure ya want me to take it?”

“What?! Three years?!”

Its sheer value had me stupefied. After all, one of my goals was to cover Maria’s medical expenses. If I sold the gem, it would resolve that problem completely.

“Then again, if ya use it, you can create something just as valuable. Coat a sword with it and you can make it nice and sturdy. But personally, I think it’d make more sense to make it into a magic item that leverages the gem, like a ring or necklace.”

“A sturdy weapon is more of a necessity for me than a magic item would be, so...”

“Well, looking at this small-scale disaster scene, I know where you’re coming from. And that certainly helps me out ’cause making weapons is more in my nature. Right then, if it’s okay with you, I suppose I’ll be taking the broken weapons and the gems it’s reasonable to take.”

“Go right ahead.”

Mr. Alibers and I made a record of the weapons and gems that were part of our transaction. We also decided on a delivery date. When I requested that a sturdy weapon be made for me as soon as possible, he gave it a little thought before making a proposal.

“If I’m to do it fast, it’d be ideal to increase my manpower. With more workers, the quality won’t suffer. If I invite a blacksmith I know who works in town, it’ll go that much faster. But if we do it that way, it’ll cost ya a fair bit more.”

“That’s okay. In the long run, it’ll be cheaper than tearing through weapon after weapon. Please do it as fast as you can.”

“Got it. Then I guess this is how much I’ll ask o’ ya... I’ll turn the gems I don’t use into money at a money-changer’s for ya too. Ya seem busy, is why.”

“Thanks. You’re helping me out a ton.”

“Now then, I’ll prepare your weapons in no time. Here’s the contract. As for the details and market prices, ask Snow over there about ’em. She may seem dopey, but she knows her stuff when it comes to that sorta thing. If I’m rippin’ ya off, don’t worry, you can come here and complain to me.”

“She does? Okay, understood.”

My eyes shifted to Snow, who was lying in the corner. I’d been thinking of asking one of the other two submasters, Palinchron or Mr. Rayle, about that kind of thing, but I guessed Snow was knowledgeable enough too.

“And now, we get into the most important topic of all.”

“The most important topic, sir?”

“Yep. We haven’t decided on the number-one most vital aspect of making a weapon.”

And here I had thought we’d talked about basically everything. But from where the blacksmith was standing, we had yet to settle on something so essential that he called it our chief concern.

“The most important? What on Earth might that be?”

“I’m talking about its design!”

I exhaled. “Its design?”

“That’s right! The look o’ the thing! The decoration! That’s more crucial than anything! Beauty beats craftsmanship! If the sword’s easy on the eyes, that’ll reflect in your gorgeous command of the blade, won’t it?!”

Oh. He’s like that.

I’d figured him for a serious person, but then again, he was right at home at Epic Seeker. His trains of thought were not on the right tracks.

“I’m trusting these weapons with my life, sir. Please focus more on the craftsmanship than on appearances.”

“That’s all the more reason! The moment you breathe your last, as your blood sprays through the air, if your sword looks too drab, you can’t call that a satisfying death, can ya?! The death of a hero’s gotta be beautiful!”

“Sir, the point of the weapon is to make sure I don’t die. I’m not sparing the moment I die any thought.”

“And that’s a bad thing, Master! While the things ya do when you’re alive are important, the way ya die’s even more important!”

“What I do while I’m alive is more important. I don’t care about what it looks like, so please make me something simple and sturdy and nothing too artsy.”

“Ya can’t mean that! Giving badass swordfighters badass swords to use is my purpose in life!”

“Consider this an order from your guildmaster. Please focus on making it durable.”

“Ha ha, hate to break it to ya, but that don’t work in Epic Seeker. We violate orders on a daily basis! Especially if following orders would make things less epic!”

“In that case, forget I said anything.”

“No, no, I’d hate that! I’m seconds away from being a part of the making of the guildmaster’s sword!”

“Then take the job seriously. I don’t want to have to take my business to some far-off atelier when there’s one so close by.”

“Urgh, then there’s nothing else for it, is there? What if I made something sturdy and then paid attention to the decorative part?”

“If all the decorative part does is make the sword a tad heavier, I’m willing to make that compromise. But I won’t pay you for that bit.”

“It can’t be helped. I’ll pay outta pocket for that part, and I’ll manage somehow.”

“Pay out of pocket? Can’t you just concede on making it ‘cool’? Is there really no other option?”

“Nope, none.”

“Seriously?”

Mr. Alibers unfurled some thick paper onto the workbench, after which he began drawing an artist’s impression with his quill.

“If you’ve got any requests, let me hear ’em. Personally, I’m thinking of making a simple straight edge with an underlying tone of white. That way I can make it nice and durable. Then I’ll apply some silverwork and engrave some letters into it with melted green gemstone. Whaddya think?”

I was captivated by the superb design he’d put onto the page. “I can’t say your obsession hasn’t borne fruit... That being said, if we’re going by what I prefer, I’d make the letters blue rather than green. Gives it a more invigorating feel.”

“So you prefer a cleaner look. Roger that. I’ll take that into account.”

“The other considerations are cohesiveness and gracefulness. A sword that lacks balance is hard to use, so please make it symmetrical.”

“Hrm, personally, I’m more of a fan of asymmetry, but oh well. I’ll make up for it with the decorative bits.”

Envisioning the end result, we knocked our preferences against each other in a lively exchange of ideas. It seemed that Mr. Alibers’s passion had sucked me in too, because I’d gotten excited myself. I could tell that the game-loving personality at my core was floating up to the surface. Mr. Alibers and I discussed the weapons for a long time, and before I knew it, the sun had set. After we’d exhausted everything we wanted to say, we bade each other goodbye with satisfied smiles on our faces.

“Be seeing ya, Master. This’ll be my first big job in a while, so forgive me if I get fired up.”

“Thank you, sir. Snow, we’re done now. Let’s go.”

I grabbed Snow, who was lying in the corner, by the scruff of her neck. The long conversation, which she’d had no interest in, had lulled her into a sound sleep. Mr. Alibers smiled slightly at the sight, and I smiled wryly back at him as I dragged her out of the atelier. With the work he would be doing, diving past Floor 20, which we were going to do starting the next day, should be easier. To be honest, today’s dive was more of a diversion than anything else. It was no exaggeration to say that the true test of our mettle lay beyond the twentieth floor.

After leaving the smith, Snow and I went into town. In order to prepare for the real dive to come, I went shopping and even stopped by a church. I was now Level 15, and as usual, I put my bonus points into magic. The number of opportunities I had to use Dimension had ratcheted up, and I couldn’t think of a better option, especially since it would increase my accuracy and precision.

In a reverie about the new swords I would get, I went back to the room where Maria was waiting for me and drew my second day on the job to a close.

Chapter 3: Reunion

Snow entered the office that was my place of work.

“Kanami,” she said as she handed me the paperwork in her hands. “Today, Epic Seeker’s on guard duty.”

“What? Guard duty?”

“The Brawl’s gonna begin soon. And that means that idiots will be coming in from outside the country. Public safety will probably take a hit. They said the stars aligned, so we should lend a hand.”

“I see. So we got them to throw a steady stint of work our way. What period of time?”

“I’m told that each guild will be taking turns working security. Our turn lasts from midday today to tonight only.”

“That’s it, huh? For now, we need to hurry and summon everybody. Snow, if you could.”

“Uh-huh.” She held up a magic gem, muttering into it to contact the guild members.

“That really is super convenient, that gem thing.”

“For the time being, I told them to get here by noon.”

“That’s all I need. Let’s decide on where they’ll be stationed by the time they arrive.”

“Do your best, Kanami!”

“Yes, yes.”

As if it was only natural, Snow started basking in the sun, sitting in a chair by the window. She clearly had no desire to help whatsoever. As I knew she disliked work that required fine details like this, I didn’t bother asking. I simply proceeded to do the work without her. To be honest, it was faster to do it alone than to receive half-assed “help.” My thinking speed was far beyond that of ordinary people anyway.

“It’s another beautiful day,” Snow commented, looking up at the sky through the window. She seemed very comfy, relishing this stretch of not doing anything in particular.

My hand didn’t stop as I gazed at her. I continued deciding on the areas each member would be in charge of. A little while later, the members who had heard the summons started entering one after another. While it wasn’t everyone, a reasonably large number of people showed up.

I launched right into a thorough explanation of the situation and told them that I would be sending them to their posts starting at noon. And thus began the day’s guild activities.

◆◆◆◆◆

Just like on my first day, I expanded Dimension across the city from my position in my office. What differed from my first day was the amount of work to be done. There were no documents on the desk. And since the members were simply policing their respective areas without a specific objective, there was no need to issue any instructions, so I had time to kill and then some.

Snow was humming a tune as she lazed around nearby. This situation had to be heaven for her. She looked like she was on Cloud Nine.

“We’ve got free time in spades, huh, Snow?”

“Free time is so wonderful. Also, I refuse to dive.”

I’d been thinking of asking her to accompany me for another dive, but she preemptively declined.

“Yeah, let’s not do the Dungeon today. Instead, would it be okay to ask you a few personal questions? You know, to kill time?” I asked, expecting to be shot down.

“Sure, I don’t mind. Just chatting isn’t a drag,” she replied, to my surprise.

I reckoned a great way to use this time was to build up a smooth and harmonious relationship of cooperation with her. First, I asked her something that had been on my mind the whole time.

“You’ve got a super famous big brother, right? Could you tell me more about him?”

Snow Walker’s brother, Glenn Walker. The strongest Dungeon diver in human history. He didn’t have to be related to her for me to be plenty interested in the man. His title was enough.

“He’s no one special. He’s pretty—no, he’s way useless. Or rather, we’re not that close, so I don’t know or care,” she said bitingly of her own brother.

“From the way you call the guy known to be humanity’s strongest ‘useless,’ it sounds to me like you are close.”

“Hmm, I dunno about that. I do talk to him, but I wouldn’t say we’re close. When we talk, it’s always just me telling him off for the stuff that makes him a good-for-nothing.”

“As a big brother myself, that makes me pity him a little. Poor Mr. Glenn Walker...”

“We’re not even blood-related, so I think it’s safe to say we aren’t close.”

“Oh, really? You’re not blood-related?”

“We’re adopted. The Walker Clan has a custom of mixing superior stock.”

“Huh, I didn’t know that. Er, the Walker Clan—that’s one of the leading noble houses of Laoravia, right?”

“Yep. The whole house is a pain. Thanks to Palinchron and Glenn, the blowback I’m getting petered out, but as a rule, they’re bossy and annoying.”

“Why? What do they tell you to do?”

“They keep telling me to make the Walker name known throughout the world like my brother. They openly stated that’s the reason they took me in.”

“Damn, now that’s an insatiable lust for fame.”

“Recently, they’ve been nagging me to get married. Before I knew it, I was betrothed to some dude I don’t even know.”

“Like one of those political marriages? I’ve never met anyone affected by one before.”

“Maybe if I make a name for myself as one of the submasters of Epic Seeker, they’ll let me be. Probably not, though,” she murmured, her expression turning depressed.

“Wait, you’re telling me you don’t wanna get married? Knowing you, I figured you’d want to get hitched to a rich person so you could kick back and relax.”

“I do need money...but getting married to a high-ranking noble wouldn’t make life any easier. It’s too much of a hassle.”

“Well, if you’re against it, I think you ought to be clear and refuse his hand. If you don’t speak up, I think you’ll regret it.”

“If I say no, it’d turn into a whole big thing. It’ll be tedious either way...and since that’s the case, better to just do nothing. It’s not like I’ve got a choice anyway.”

“What do you mean, you’ve got no choice?”

“Try as I might, it’s all pointless in the end.”

That was the moment I sensed just how warped Snow’s view of life was. She was so checked out that she’d even given up on her own marriage. In fact, to my eyes, she’d given up on life. Nothing on the planet mattered to her, hence how noncommittal she was and how slow she was to react to the world. No wonder she always wanted to slack off. It was heartbreaking. Some part of my soul was screaming that I couldn’t let her be so resigned to her fate.

“So, tell me, what’s made you this apathetic? Is it something that happened to you in the past?”

“Boy, you’re really stabbing straight to the heart of things,” she said, taken aback. She chuckled despite herself.

“Sorry,” I replied. “I know I’m overstepping. It’s just that since we’re partners, I wanna get to know you sooner rather than later. I get the feeling that if I don’t, that’s something I’ll regret.” Something inside me that I couldn’t identify compelled me to keep flapping my gums.

“Oh well, I don’t really mind. Not if it’s you.”

“If I recall correctly, you’ve been a submaster of Epic Seeker since you were a little kid, right? Was it around then that something happened?”

“Back in the day, I still had the innocence of a little kid. I was enthusiastic about doing guild work, and I had fun every day, because back then, I had my dreams.”

“Wow, you being enthusiastic? I’m having trouble picturing that.”

“In those days, I’d only failed once, so I had hope. But after messing up more times than I could count, giving it my all started feeling stupid and ridiculous. And that’s how I got this way. That’s literally it.”

“So it was a big string of failures. I see.”

When she said the words “failed” and “messing up,” her expression turned sour. That was the first unguarded facial expression the always-phoning-it-in Snow had ever shown me. And for some reason, I got the feeling that I understood where she was coming from. At least somewhat.

“Yeah. That’s why I just can’t be assed anymore. The more frantic I got, the more of an idiot I felt like. If I genuinely try and then fail, I’ll feel like total shit. And I just don’t wanna go through that anymore,” she said, a humorless smile pasted onto her face.

On an intellectual level, I knew I was supposed to tell her she was wrong, but my heart wouldn’t let me. And that was because I knew what she was talking about. I could sympathize. Most of all, I hesitated to take her to task after she had been willing to divulge the unvarnished truth about herself.

“Color me a little surprised. I didn’t think you were the type to be so open, Snow. Guess I just had to ask.”

“Actually, it’s because I think we’re birds of a feather. I know that you messed up big time too, Kanami.”

“I messed up big time? What do you—ackh?!” I’d detected something through Dimension.

“What’s wrong, Kanami?”

On the very edge of Dimension’s ambit, I spotted some folks about to get into a quarrel with a member of Epic Seeker. Two girls had approached our guild member and were sounding off at them.

“Someone’s flaring up at one of our people.”

“Wait, they’re accosting a guild member? Not just one of the townsfolk?”

I intensified Dimension into Layered Dimension so that I could get a better grasp of the situation. The two girls were abnormal. That was the adjective that jumped out at me before any other. That was how unusual they were. They both had flowing blonde hair like golden sand in the wind. One had her long hair in a braid hanging down her back. Upon closer inspection, it wasn’t just blonde; she also had hairs that were closer to silver. It had a wondrous glow to it, a tangle of glittering gold and silver. And her body was beyond the ordinary too. Her face was so pretty that it looked inhuman, and her golden eyes were out-of-this-world gorgeous. Then, there were her absolutely perfect proportions. She was like an embodiment of beauty, surpassing the heights of feminine allure so utterly that it was nigh monstrous.

“There’s a girl who’s, like, scary pretty.”

“Scary pretty?”

The other girl was anomalous in her own right. She was on the short side, and she wore her hair short, with a ponytail in the back. She was androgynous and could pass for a handsome boy as well. Needless to say, she was also frighteningly beautiful. In terms of feminine beauty, the other girl had her beat, but the second one did have an androgynous charm all her own. Could the pair maybe be sisters?

“Yeah. She’s pretty but scary. And there are actually two girls like that.”

“Could they by any chance be...”

“Whoa, who are they?! There’s abnormal and then there’s this!”

That was how eye-popping their stats were.

【STATUS】

NAME: Lastiara Whoseyards

HP: 708/709

MP: 325/325

CLASS: None

LEVEL 16

STR 11.73

VIT 11.12

DEX 7.14

AGI 8.40

INT 12.98

MAG 9.13

APT 4.00

CONDITION: None

INNATE SKILLS: Weapon Combat 2.14, Swordplay 2.03, Pseudo-Divine Eyes 1.00

Magical Combat 2.27, Bloodknack 5.00, Holy Magic 1.03

ACQUIRED SKILLS: Book Reading 0.52, Doll Body 1.00

【STATUS】

NAME: Diablo Sith

HP: 179/182

MP: 821/831

CLASS: Swordfighter

LEVEL 11

STR 6.32

VIT 5.39

DEX 3.02

AGI 3.18

INT 9.99

MAG 45.12

APT 5.00

CONDITION: Protection 1.00

INNATE SKILLS: Holy Magic 3.80, Divine Protection 3.08, Condemn 2.00, Concentration 2.05,

Elemental Magic 2.10, Overprotection 2.12, Life Support 2.24, Targeting 2.03

ACQUIRED SKILLS: Swordplay 0.10

???: ???

Nonstandard APT and skills, and numbers that were an order of magnitude higher than average on top of that. The thought that these two girls, this Lastiara and Diablo, had come anywhere near the members of my guild dismayed me. After all, if they ever got serious, our people would be slaughtered, helpless to stop them. And judging by what I was seeing, the chances were high that a fight was imminent.

“Snow, come out here! Now! They’re so strong that only we can stand against them!”

“I...guess I have to, huh?”

She got to her feet without grumbling—she knew this was no trifling matter. After checking that she was coming with me, I jumped out the window.

While running across the rooftops, I had Snow, who was behind me, contact the other guild members nearby through the magic gems, telling them to gather. I wasn’t planning on having those members fight, but they could give off an intimidating aura just by encircling the strangers. For the sake of the guild member that the two superstrong girls were harassing, the gears in my head whirred at their very fastest as I issued orders.

I ran with all my might, hoping that a fight wouldn’t break out before I got there. By the time I arrived, the members of Epic Seeker and the two girls had moved to a back alley so as not to cause a commotion. In the darkness of that alleyway, the taller girl was yelling at the members who had surrounded them.

“Oh c’mon! Just take me to where Palinchron is already!”

I hurried into the alley. “Wait! If you’ve got something to say, I’ll hear you out! I’m the guildmaster of Epic Seeker, Aikawa Kanami!”

Just as I’d been aiming for, the girls shifted their attention away from the guild members to me. And then their eyes opened wide, like they couldn’t believe what they were seeing.

“Huh? Wait, what? Sieg?!”

The braided girl looked befuddled as she turned to face me.

“Palinchron’s one of my subordinates! If you’ve got business with him, I’ll tell him for you, so I’ll thank you to step away from my guild members!”

The androgynous girl in the back was the next to speak. “Sieg?! It’s me! Dia!”

Dia. Must be short for Diablo. But something’s weird. Despite me telling them my name’s Aikawa Kanami, they keep calling me “Sieg.” The same name that Snow mentioned.

“Got it. So your name’s Dia, then. In any case, do me the favor of stepping away from them.”

While there were a bunch of things that stuck out to me as concerning, priority number one was securing my people’s safety. The braided girl complied and put some distance between them and herself, visibly pondering as she did so. The girl who went by Dia, on the other hand, started walking toward me. “Sieg! What’re you talking about?! C’mon, let’s just go back together!”

“Go back?”

I had no idea what this Diablo Sith person was on about. She got my very name wrong, so it couldn’t be helped.

“What’ve you been doing this whole time?! If you aren’t hurt, why didn’t you come to Greeard?!”

“Stop right there! Dia, was it?! Don’t come any closer!”

This Diablo Sith was well past the ordinary; I fetched a sword from my inventory and stood at the ready. At the sight of it, she froze. At first, I’d thought she’d seized up with fear, but I was mistaken. She pointed at it and muttered.

“Huh? Sieg... What happened to my sword?”

“Your sword? Hold on. I honestly haven’t got a clue what you’re saying. For starters, my name isn’t ‘Sieg’ or whatever. Are you mistaking me for someone else?”

With a stiff smile and a not exactly composed expression, she sidled up to me. “Mistaking you for someone else? How could I possibly not know you, Sieg? I’m the one who’s got no idea what you’re saying. C’mon, buddy—enough joking around! It’s a pretty nasty joke too! Without you, I... I...”

Trembling at the bizarre vibe she was giving off, I shouted on the spur of the moment. “I... I’m telling you, stop right there!”

Her abilities, words, and actions were all extremely threatening. And the way her eyes had gradually begun to lose their glow gave me chills.

“Ha, ha ha,” she said, gazing at me with hollow eyes. “Why are you pretending not to know me? And why that sword? Why my sword? Tell me, won’t you? What’s wrong? Are you leaving me to the wolves?”

She was smiling, but her eyes were overflowing with sorrow. It looked like she was in a state of confusion, faced with a truth she had trouble accepting.

“I’m sorry, but I don’t know you,” I answered honestly after ascertaining that the guild members had fled to the safe zone. “I don’t know anything. I’ve never met a girl that’s anything like you before, to begin with.”

She was grimacing something fierce now. “Huh?”

The thought of this powder keg of a girl falling into a state of shock had me in a cold sweat. I replied gently and tenderly in hopes of defusing the situation. “I’m not whoever Sieg is. I’m Aikawa Kanami. With that in mind, I’d like to hear what you have to say. Otherwise, I’ll remain unable to grasp what you’re saying.”

In response, she crumpled to her knees, clearly not of sound mind. “Augh...not...not again, surely? Ah...am I getting tossed aside again?”

“Calm down. Please. I never said I wouldn’t hear you out. If you could just take your time and explain your situation—”

She sobbed loudly before hunching over and shedding tears. “Hic...hic...wahhhhhh!!!”

“What, huh? Why are you crying? Hey, please don’t cry! Look, I’ve got no animosity toward you. And I’m gonna stow my sword away. See?”

Diablo Sith’s sudden wailing bewildered me. Her stats had made me assume that she had ample emotional fortitude to go with her raw power, but it was the exact opposite. Her heart was so brittle, in fact, that it made me feel like a fool for rushing over in such a panicked frenzy.

“Oh, would you look at that, you went and made her cry. Bad boy!” The braided girl who had been watching from behind, Lastiara Whoseyards, walked forward to pat Diablo Sith on the head.

“I made her cry?! I’m totally lost here! Who or what are you two?!”

Chapter 4: Some Quick and Easy Guild Work

Early the next morning, Snow and I went to a church to do our prayers in order to convert the EXP we’d accumulated into a proper level-up. I was now Level 16, and Snow was Level 17.

Come nighttime, our new weapons would be complete. I knew that without the weapons, we’d just be wasting gear on Floor 27. While we wondered how to occupy our time until sundown, we tried to return to the guild. However, when I saw the crowd at the entrance, I stopped. If I remembered correctly, there shouldn’t have been any guild work today, and yet...

“Did something happen?” I asked the crowd as their Guildmaster.

The eyes of the people gathered by the entrance fell on me. Our gazes met, and I was amazed at the high-level members of the crowd. I didn’t need my menu-sight to be able to tell. The quality of the magic energy spilling out of their bodies spoke to their strength. Perhaps because my level had risen and the accuracy of my dimensional magic had increased, I got the feeling that my understanding of the magic energy in the air had likewise improved.

From among the crowd, a man with particularly potent magic energy stepped forward.

“That face. Am I correct in assuming you’re the guildmaster of Epic Seeker?”

“Uh, yes, I am.”

“Allow me to introduce myself. I’m the guildmaster of Supreme, Elmirahd Siddark. Nice to meet you.”

The man with the excess of magic energy proffered a hand. I used Analyze as I gripped it.

【STATUS】

NAME: Elmirahd Siddark

HP: 200/201

MP: 299/299

CLASS: Knight

LEVEL 20

STR 4.79

VIT 2.81

DEX 4.12

AGI 7.29

INT 7.19

MAG 18.09

APT 1.67

INNATE SKILLS: Elemental Magic 1.92

ACQUIRED SKILLS: Magical Combat 1.88, Swordplay 0.89

He was indisputably a man of extraordinary talent. Elemental magic was his innate skill, and his magic power was a cut above. In addition, his level and skills were high for his age; he must have been working hard from early on. His blond hair flowed freely down to his shoulders, and his almond-shaped eyes stood out. His attire was the garb of nobility, and his bearing was firm and resolute. The overall impression I got was one of cunning.

“Damn! You’re after me now?!”

“Look this way, mister.”

It was damn near teleportation. Taken aback by her effectively warping behind me, I unsheathed my sword and looked over my shoulder. She had a big smile on her face. It was the innocent smile of a child who’d pulled off some kind of prank. She put her hand on my shoulder. Then she poked my cheek.

“Hee hee, got you to look!”

I jumped away from her. Pain and heat racked the nape of my neck. “Yowch!”

My sword was trained on her as I put a hand to my neck. I didn’t sense an ounce of hostility from her, but the chances I’d been hit with some kind of attack were high.

After I gained some distance on the gleeful little girl, Mr. Lorwen attacked her.

“Reaper! Don’t drag strangers into this!”

“You’re too late, Lorwen! The boy’s mine now!”

The girl flew away from Mr. Lorwen. It didn’t take long to comprehend what she meant by that. I focused Dimension on the heat in my neck. A black symbol resembling a magic circle was now floating over that spot, and it emitted heat as it siphoned away my magic energy. Dimension informed me that the energy was flowing into the girl called Reaper. Looking closely, a symbol similar to the one on my neck had appeared at some point on her forehead. Some kind of link had been created between the two symbols; there could be no doubt that she was currently draining my magic energy.

“Hee hee! The devil’s behind you now. The space behind you, my darling... it belongs to me and only me,” she incanted. She absorbed my energy, and now she was bursting with power. “I am the one, the only, Grim Rim Reaper! Talk about a coincidence! This boy is the same as him! Hee hee hee! He’s another dimension mage! And would you look at that! I just filled my caster-mage vacancy using him! Now then, Lorwen, what’re you gonna do?!”

Whenever she shouted and made her power swell, more magic energy leaked from me. She was doubtless only surviving off the energy she was taking from me. Mr. Lorwen groaned and came over to me.

“Damn, no choice now! What’s your name, kid?!”

“Kanami,” I said, still with a hand to my neck. “My name is Aikawa Kanami.”

While I could sense a wickedness in the girl, I didn’t sense any malice from the Guardian. I concluded that telling him my name couldn’t hurt.

“Ai... Aikawa Kanami?!” he shouted in surprise.

Apparently, my name rang a bell. However, Mr. Lorwen only gave a look of surprise for a brief space of time, and then quickly closed his mouth and returned to a serious expression.

“Sorry, Kanami! I’ll be needing you to cooperate! If you wanna undo that curse, we have to take her down!”

“I... I don’t really get what’s happening, but I do know that that girl is bad news! And that I can’t afford to let things play out!”

I now understood that holding my neck was doing nothing to stem the flow of energy, so I accepted Mr. Lorwen’s proposal.

“Hee hee, heh heh heh, ah ha ha, AH HA HA HA HA HA!”

I brandished my sword side by side with the Guardian as we stared down the grim reaper girl who was merrily laughing her head off. This was completely different from my initial plan, but it couldn’t be helped. I had to do something about the foe before my eyes before I could touch the Guardian. I started thinking about the optimal plan to defeat her.

The next moment, her giant scythe smashed the surrounding crystal to pieces. I dodged the attack by a nose as I asked him a question—I needed information to be able to do anything at all.

“Mr. Lorwen! Is that thing a monster or what?!”

“No, it’s not! And of course, it’s not a Guardian or a human either! It’s just a spell! It’s a spell with a mind of its own!”

“A spell?!” The possibility hadn’t crossed my mind.

“Yep. It’s a curse created solely to kill me. The spell used a fairy tale as its motif, and the spell’s name is Grim Rim Reaper. Please fight while keeping that story in mind!”

“Wait, did you...did you say fairy tales?! Sorry, but I don’t know that one!” I’d never heard of the Grim Rim Reaper.

“But I mean, everyone knows that story the world over!”

“I’m telling you, I really don’t know it!” However famous the story was, I wasn’t from this world.

I kept dodging her aiming-for-my-blind-spot scythe swings, the look on my face ever serious. Mr. Lorwen could tell from my expression that I wasn’t lying.

“Okay! I’ll give you the gist! She can’t exist while you’re looking at her; she only takes form when you’re not looking at her. She’s the villain in the fairy tale and acts according to that rule. She’ll attack from outside your field of vision, so hit her using counterattacks!”

“She only takes form when you don’t see her? Okay, got it!”

That was all she needed to be a thorn in my side. Sure, she was a spell as opposed to an organism, but that was still an overpowered ability. She could attack from all directions, teleporting and then swinging, teleporting and then swinging, and while I could dodge, countering her scythe stroke was easier said than done.

There was something unnatural about her onslaught, though. When facing Mr. Lorwen, she exuded a hair-raising bloodlust, but she had no bloodlust toward me at all. And I got the feeling she was actively avoiding swinging for my vitals too.

I had Mr. Lorwen’s back. Irritated, she backed away a little and huffed indignantly. “Oh, for goodness’ sake! Would you get out of my hair, mister?! I just wanna kill Lorwen!”

“Er, so uh, you don’t plan on killing me, then?”

“Of course not. You’re what I’m feeding on, mister. I’d just be crippling myself.”

“What you’re...feeding on... I don’t suppose you could quit draining my energy for the time being, huh?”

“No duh! If I stopped, I’d stop being in fighting form, so I’ll drain you till death do us part!”

“You’re gonna drain me to death? In that case, what choice do I have but to fight you?”

I gripped my blade anew and glared at her, but I couldn’t muster the will to kill her either. Her looking human was already enough to make slaying her difficult. Her reacting to stuff in that childlike way only dampened my fighting spirit even more.

“Kanami, it’s no use! Once the curse is on you, it’ll just keep draining your energy until you die!” the Guardian cried.

But I didn’t believe him, partly because I wasn’t going to swallow wholesale whatever somebody I just met said, but mostly because I didn’t get the sense that the danger was quite as bad as he was making it out to be. It was true that my energy was getting sucked out of me, but that was hardly going to kill me. It was leaking from my body a tiny bit at a time, like through a thin straw. And while it would hinder combat a little for me, it wasn’t life-or-death. Or at least, it shouldn’t be.

She processed the energy she was taking from me with apparent relish and started crafting a spell. “Hee hee! What juicy magic energy! I’m thinking I’m in finer form than before! Now it’ll be child’s play to escape from your gazes!”

It looked as though this spell could cast its own spell. “Spellcast: Dimension: Nightmare!”

It was very similar to my magic, and not just because it contained the word Dimension in its name. It was clearly the same school of spell. And that wasn’t all. Even the idea of tacking a word like “nightmare” onto the spell’s name sounded like something I’d do.

Floor 30 became filled with dimension-element magic, black bubbles suddenly appearing within that domain. Using Dimension, I gleaned the full picture of her magic. In essence, it wasn’t all that different from Dimension. I also detected that the black bubbles were packed with teleportation magic. It was a lot like Snowmension in that way. As for why the bubbles were black, it was probably to block the enemy’s vision even as it conquered the space on the battlefield.

As promised, she made her body disappear and teleported to our blind spot. I immediately expanded Dimension out wide and eliminated it as a blind spot. However, her own Dimension: Nightmare grasped the expansion of my Dimension, pinpointing where the expansion was thinnest and moving to that spot.

Though Dimension was a spell that gathered information about space, it didn’t always do so automatically. For the most part, I had to think about what information I wanted. In other words, unless I was painstakingly meticulous, there would invariably be a small gap somewhere. And she was traveling within those gaps. It was a battle of precision between Dimensions.

She appeared near Mr. Lorwen’s rear and slashed at him laterally. He wrenched himself out of the way, but if I wasn’t mistaken, it looked like the scythe had grazed the hem of his clothes. Right before the sickle could do more damage, I perceived her using Dimension, so the weapon had lost its physical form.

Seeing that she’d failed to even hit his hem, she pouted. She slashed at Mr. Lorwen over and over, but each and every time, my Dimension “saw” her, making her sickle fail to reach its target.

“Grr! I’m so fed up! Your stupid magic’s getting in my way!”

She changed targets to me. It seemed she had no means of getting around Dimension. Focusing on me, she tried to strengthen the link between her and the emblem on my nape.

“I’ll just drain more of your energy and leave you unable to use that spell!”

Mr. Lorwen grew flustered. “Kanami, fall back for now—”

“That’s okay, Mr. Lorwen,” I replied quietly. “I’ve got this. I get it now.”

I had collected enough information on her. Her unique ability had taken me by surprise at first, but now I was used to it.

I ignored her and crafted a different spell. To be frank, this piddly little curse-link could never drain me dry. It was like pricking a hole in a giant silo with a needle. It had no real impact when it came to the larger picture.

“I’ll switch all my magic energy usage to Layered Dimension and prioritize my space-sight.”

I intensified my perception field, filling the entire space and eliminating any unseen spot for her to materialize in. There were no more places where it was thin either. I left zero holes through which she could get the jump on us. That was all I had to do to utterly incapacitate her.

“Wait, huh?! What the?!”

Through her Dimension: Nightmare, she’d detected that my magic energy now permeated every square inch of Floor 30. She turned her body to mist and teleported around, darting from black bubble to black bubble and leaping through space, only to find herself unable to ever actually materialize.

“Huh? There’s nowhere I’m not seen?!” Sweat beaded on her forehead and she grimaced.

“Give it up. As long as I’m anywhere near you, you’ll never be able to materialize again. I won’t miss one millimeter or one second of time, and I’ll never let you go.”

Dimension’s gaze captured every microsecond she teleported. By perceiving the flow of magic energy, I could even predict where she’d teleport to next. Moreover, I’d already finished analyzing the hundred-plus black bubbles. With that, she was left with no means of doing us harm. And as long as she couldn’t attack us with her scythe, it was checkmate.

“You can’t be serious! You snake! That’s beyond messed up! I can’t!”

After repeatedly teleporting, the incensed reaper tried to hit my body with both hands. As she was still unable to materialize, she couldn’t even touch me.

“Phew. Glad I happened to have a spell that’s handy against her. I’m gonna take a breather for now.”

I took a deep breath, relieved that the rapid-fire action had finally come to a stop. And it appeared that Mr. Lorwen understood that as well, as he saw how neutralized she was. He relaxed and came over to us.

“Damn, Kanami, you’re something else! But are you sure your magic energy ain’t running out?”

“It’s not really that bad, mister. Honestly, it isn’t something I might die from.”

Lorwen started ruminating with a serious expression. “It’s not that bad? Is it our location? Or is your magic energy just that huge?”

Seeing him at such a loss to explain it, the girl floated closer. She knew it was pointless to struggle, so she’d made her scythe vanish. I stood at the ready against her, but she addressed the Guardian with a lighthearted tone.

“I think that’s just how much magic energy he’s got compared to you. Unlike you, mister’s got loads and loads. I’m draining away, but he’s still got strength to spare. And even worse, it’s super effective against me!”

“Is the gap between us that big?” Lorwen replied equally casually.

“Yep. If he’s a richly flavored apple, you’re dried fruit.”

“Well, I’m sorry I’ve got such low magic energy! Actually, I’m average, if anything!”

“Quit yelling at me! In any case, he won’t meet the end you thought he’d meet. I think a boy like him can probably keep me going indefinitely.”

“He can keep you alive? You’re kidding me.”

It seemed Lorwen could scarcely believe what she’d concluded. And for some reason, he appeared to be somewhat worried about her. I was the one who couldn’t believe what I was hearing; these two had been trying to kill each other moments prior, and now they were chatting as though that fight hadn’t just happened. They were too buddy-buddy. I was even inclined to think the two were old friends. I figured I should learn more about the situation, so I butted into their conversation.

“Er, if I may?”

“Hm? What’s up, kid?” He stopped ruminating and looked my way with a placid expression.

“It’s just, I came all the way down here to take down the Guardian of Floor 30, so...”

“Oh yeah, now that you mention it, I’m a Dungeon Guardian,” he said, his benign expression unchanging. “So much happened that I forgot.”

This wasn’t going to script, to say the least. Wasn’t a Guardian supposed to be a merciless, unfeeling monster? Wasn’t a Guardian the kind of mad beast that attacked any humans it encountered, leaving countless casualties in its wake? That was what I’d been told, and yet...

“Wait,” said the girl, “you came to kill Lorwen? Then let’s kill him together! I’d have liked to have killed him by myself, but I don’t mind bringing you aboard!”

She was the one who supplied all the mercilessness and madness, not Lorwen. I did want to talk to her too, eventually, but Mr. Lorwen was the priority at the moment.

“Hold... Hold on a second. Er...Reaper? Let me talk with Mr. Lorwen first.” I didn’t know what to call her at first, but I settled on just calling her Reaper.

“Hmph! Don’t leave me out! Let me in on it!”

“I’m not leaving you out of anything. I’ll listen to you later on, so for now, be good and—”

“No way, no how! I know how this goes! You say that now, but you just plan to ignore me in the end!”

“I can assure you that’s—”

“Hey, forget about that and undo your spell already! With magic like that, I can’t touch anyth—”

“Spellcast: Wintermension.”

“Wait, huh?! It... It hurts! It hurts!”

I activated a limited version of Wintermension, the target being the curse-link stretching to her from the emblem on the nape of my neck. It was the same process as when I impeded other people’s magic. All I did was apply Wintermension’s vibration-damping ability to suppress the flow, and that was enough to stem the transfer of magic energy to her. In fact, if I wanted to, I could reverse the flow and drain her energy.

Cut off from her supply, she began to suffocate. The only reason I’d left her alone even though she was draining my magic energy was because I was confident that I could do this at any time. I quickly restored her supply and chided her.

“Now be quiet.”

“Yes, sir,” she said, looking extremely spooked. “Even the way he scolds people is the same as him,” she muttered as she backed down dejectedly. Clearly, she had some trauma with regard to what I’d just done.

I’d been bailed out by how effective my dimensional magic happened to be against Reaper; she was shut down completely. But something was nagging at me a little. Even if Reaper was a spell created by some mage, it felt too convenient. It was almost like the spell had been cast knowing I’d be using it...

You know what, I’ll think about that later. First, I have to talk to Mr. Lorwen.

“Er, first things first, are you really the Guardian of Floor 30, mister?”

“Sorry, kid, but could you cool it with the ‘mister’ and the formality? It’s bothering me.”

“Huh? You mean my formal register?”

“Physically, we’re basically the same age. Please just talk casually.”

It was true that appearance-wise, we weren’t all that many years apart. Mr. Lorwen looked older than me, but not by much.

“Got it, Lorwen. And you can just call me Kanami too.”

“Of course, Kanami. Now then, what was the question again? Was it whether I’m a Guardian or not?”

“I’m having trouble believing you could be a Guardian. Reaper, on the other hand, I could believe.”

“Nope. That nitwit just came with the package. During the last moments of the ritual, she was near me, so she got wrapped up in it, that’s all. I’m definitely the Guardian here.”

“So you’re a monster, then?”

“Yep, I’m a monster. Only, unlike the other dudes, I haven’t fully fallen yet, so I’m still mostly human-looking.” Lorwen shifted his eyes to his own body. He was the very picture of a normal human being.

“Damn, for real? That’s a problem. I came here because I thought there was a boss monster to kill.”

“Oh, you don’t gotta worry about that. I can’t die like a person dies. You’re good to face me like you would a monster.”

“You can’t die like a person dies? What’s that mean?”

“The moment my heart stops beating, my transformation into a monster is complete. And if you beat me, you officially clear the Trigesimal Trial. Wanna go at it now?”

“I dunno. You still look too human to fight to kill.”

“Yeah, guess I don’t blame ya... If I were in your shoes, I wouldn’t be able to draw my own sword either.” Mr. Lorwen shrugged with a sheepish smile.

This truly put me in a bind. At this rate, I wouldn’t be able to fulfill my end of Palinchron’s bargain. I hadn’t imagined the Guardian would be this understanding. From what I’d heard, when Guardians in the past had manifested, it had resulted in lots of casualties, but Mr. Lorwen seemed to be different. Was the play to force his heart to stop and turn him into a monster? I figured I’d be able to point my sword at him if he looked the part. Probably.

“Hrm. In that case, let’s make a deal,” suggested Mr. Lorwen.

“Huh? A deal?”

Yet another deal. A deal with Lorwen in order to cash in on Palinchron’s deal. It reminded me of chains of fetch quests and errands in an RPG. Go do this for me. Go do that for me. Meanwhile, the main story thread is put on the back burner. That happened all the time in video games. I had half a mind to ignore all of it and just level grind. After all, as long as I could do something about that pair of girls, I was pretty much golden.

“Yep, and it’s a simple one. Grant me my heart’s desire. If you do, I’ll die.”

“If I grant your heart’s desire, you’ll die? Is that really true?”

“Us Guardians are dead to begin with. Our lingering attachments keep our bodies animated, but that doesn’t mean we’re alive. As such, if we lose those attachments, we start growing weaker, and if we fulfill our driving ambition, we disappear.”

Mr. Lorwen had said he was already dead. It seemed the reason he’d said I could treat him as a monster to slay was because he had already braced himself for death. I was speechless, but he continued.

“In fact, dying is what I want. So you don’t have to worry. You can aim for my life.”

He smiled faintly. I knew he was being considerate, trying to lessen my anxiety however he could. And I figured it was only right I repay his kindness.

“Understood. If you insist, I’ll resolve to kill the Guardian through that method.”

“Thanks, Kanami.”

We shook on it. We’d only known each other for a short while, but I could tell that Lorwen wasn’t a bad person, and as such, I was willing to cooperate with him. Of course, it was also a self-interested move. Lorwen was strong. He was so capable, in fact, that he could dodge a hyperspeed scythe coming at him from his blind spot with ease while unarmed. I had no doubt that he’d be quite the asset against those two overpowered girls. Depending on the contents of our deal, he might become my ally up until he fulfilled his heart’s desire.

“No, you can’t!” shouted Reaper, unable to stay quiet anymore. “I’m gonna be the one to kill Lorwen, so there’s no way I can let him die like that!”

It seemed Reaper was obsessed with murdering Lorwen by her own hand. And considering she was a spell cast for the sole purpose of killing him, I perhaps couldn’t blame her for reaching that conclusion.

“Look, I’m telling ya, the dude who ordered you to kill me is dead now. Man, have you got a thick skull. You ain’t got no reason to kill me anymore.”

“I understand that...but...but then what am I supposed to do? What reason have I got to go on living?”

“Decide for yourself,” he said, his tone strong and firm. “That’s what life’s about. Having your purpose in life decided for you before you’re born ain’t how it usually is. You need to live and search for what to do with your life.”

I felt the same way. I was of the opinion that, at the very least, making it one’s purpose in life to kill somebody was wrong.

“But... But that’s hard...” she said, close to tears as she turned back into black mist.

“Hey, wait! Where are you going?!” shouted Lorwen.

I knew where Reaper was fleeing, though. Or rather, she made it crystal clear to me. Because the black mist went inside of me. At first, I thought I’d reject her entry using Wintermension, but her sorrowful expression made me feel bad for her, so I ended up letting her inside.

“Lorwen. Reaper went inside me. And she’s all withdrawn and sulky.”

“Inside you? I...see. That’s good,” he said, relieved to hear that Reaper was okay. Apparently, he was concerned about the fate of the curse that had been so intent on killing him. He was like a big brother fretting over his ill-behaving sister.

“But my body feels kinda heavy now.”

“I mean, yeah. Reaper’s a curse. That’s only natural if you’re shouldering a top-level curse.”

“Wha... What do I do with her?”

“Well, Reaper may be a dumbass, but she’s not a bad kid. If you can reason with her, she’s a spell you can make use of. Congrats, Kanami. From this day forward, you’re the owner of a legendary death spirit.” The look in his eyes said he’d found someone to take care of his dumb little sister.

“I’d like to pass, if possible.”

Lorwen may have been cool with it, but there was no way I’d agree to this. It wouldn’t kill me, but it did put a drain on my precious MP.

“Sorry, sorry. I was just joking. I’ll help you drive Reaper out. We’ll find a mage to replace you. Or if we can seal her away, that’d be good too... Unfortunately, magic’s outside my area of expertise, so there’s nothing I can do. Hey, are any other Guardians alive and kicking?”

“No. I’m told both the Guardian of Floor 10 and the Guardian of Floor 20 are dead.”

“Damn, if a Guardian who specialized in magic were around, we might’ve been able to save her. But they’re dead, huh? They’ve all disappeared.”

Lorwen spoke of saving Reaper without missing a beat. The two had been trying to kill each other before, but it seemed that wasn’t all there was to their relationship. I intended to learn more about them little by little, but now that things had settled down, I wanted to ask him about the number-one most important thing. For indeed, it didn’t get more important...

“So, Lorwen, what’s your heart’s desire?”

...than the method by which I could kill the Thief of Earth’s Essence.

“My heart’s desire, huh? Let me think. I feel like there was a lot,” he said, less than articulately. Gradually, he unearthed the memory, changing his expression countless times as he strung together his next sentence. “If I recall, my biggest wish was to become a famous knight, I think.” He opened and closed his empty right hand as he continued talking to himself. “Yeah, that’s right. My desire was to show the world my sword skills. That was my dream since I was a kid. I know that’s what it is. I know for a fact that that wish was a thing.”

Embarrassed by the childishness of his own dream, he nevertheless stated it to me. His expression became assured.

“Yeah. What I want is prestige and glory. I want the masses to sing my praises as a hero.”

With a boyish grin, he let spill his very simple wish. It was so innocent, so pure...and sad and empty, in a way.

“Otherwise, I’ll have no recompense,” he muttered, leaving his confession at that.

I wasn’t imagining it. If I squinted, he looked positively forlorn.

If his explanation was true, it was an ability that resembled Dimension a great deal. Actually, it was stronger than Dimension, considering Lorwen didn’t need to expend any MP to activate it.

“Maybe you’re thinking it’s similar to your own magic, but it’s different, technically. Your dimensional magic allows you to grasp everything on an intellectual level, while this is way more instinctive by comparison. It’s a technique to comprehend the flow and the natural ways of this world intuitively.”

Until now, most of the sword techniques were rational and based on precise calculations. That this final technique was based on such an ambiguous and vague power had me scratching my head.

“With this power, no matter what situation you may find yourself in, even if you’re out of magic energy, you’ll be able to fight against Reaper. And if you combine it with your dimensional magic, your comprehension power ought to power up, becoming more accurate than ever before.”

“All right, I’ll try doing it too.” I closed my eyes, quelled my magic energy, and cleared my mind, mimicking Lorwen’s technique by following what I’d observed. But all I was doing was standing in place. I heard his foot skid on the ground, and I braced myself—

“Ow!”

The next instant, he flicked me on the forehead. My eyes flew open.

“Sorry, you did it wrong.”

“Huh? What’d I do wrong? Hold on. I’ll try again.”

“It’s good to challenge yourself.”

I attempted it again, the same way as before. This time around, I held nothing back. I perfectly mimicked the information I’d gleaned down to the most minute detail. His heartbeats, the amount of perspiration, his breathing—I brought myself closer and closer to all of it. I even reenacted where he’d tensed his muscles to a tee, let alone his posture. I sharpened my senses and waited for him to come at me with his forehead finger fl—

“Ow!”

I couldn’t block it.

“Hmm,” said Lorwen. “You’re not picking it up as quickly all of a sudden.”

“Oh c’mon! There’s no way I can understand my surroundings with my eyes closed and without using any magic energy!”

“But you can. You saw it yourself; I was using this skill to dodge Reaper’s blind-spot attacks.”

“But how can that possibly be?! You’re... You’re not doing anything!”

That’s right. This skill involves not doing anything. And if you don’t do anything, you can’t grasp any information. That’s the logical conclusion.

“It’s because I’m not doing anything that I understand. It’s less a technique of the body and more a technique of the mind. Looks like you may be able to mimic things on an external level, you can’t on an internal level. Basically, it’s your headspace that must be tripping you up.”

“Hold on, there’s no way my headspace will solve the problem!” I couldn’t comprehend what he was saying.

“And here I thought this skill was ideally suited to you, Kanami.”

I shook my head frantically, and he gave me a pitying look, which didn’t amuse me. After all, the chance that this was a unique skill that only he could perform was high. In fact, I was sure of it. That’d make sense of things. A technique of the mind like the Responsiveness skill? I’d never—

“Your mind and body are kinda disconnected,” he continued.

He drew closer and put a hand on my forehead. Then he closed his eyes, as if he were feeling around inside my heart. I didn’t feel any magic energy in his hand. Even if I activated Dimension, I still wouldn’t know what he was doing. For all intents and purposes, he had his hand on my forehead and that was that. Despite that, he perceived the state of my heart and voiced what he was sensing.

“Not only are they disconnected, you’ve also got a ton of chains binding ya, it looks like. Sturdy, constricting chains.”

“You can even grasp stuff like that through Responsiveness?”

“It’s because this skill is more or less the utmost peak a human can reach, though it has a drawback, in that as a sort of enlightenment, it’s hard to learn.”

“A sort of enlightenment? You...were gonna teach me something that, well, ultimate?”

“I thought you’d be able to learn.”

“But, like, there’s no way I could achieve enlightenment that easily.”

I cursed how difficult the trial Lorwen had assigned me was. In my world, enlightenment was the stuff of fairy tales, something that a handful, if not fewer, of our grand forefathers might or might not reach in their lifetimes. How could an idiot like me come shoulder to shoulder with the greats?

Lorwen forcefully dismissed that idea. “You’ve got that backwards. It’d be stranger if you didn’t reach it easily. That’s how silly strong you are.”

I didn’t know what to say to that. I didn’t think he was talking solely about my dimensional magic or my Aptitude or what have you. I had a feeling he was talking about something more fundamental. About everything I’d been gifted in this world. The way this world seemed so partial to me.

“Maybe what that Lastiara Whoseyards girl said was on the money. I can’t state anything definitively, but it’s true that your heart’s in no normal state.”

“So you think so too.”

“Yeah, I do. My Responsiveness skill is telling me your mental condition is off...but I won’t say anything beyond that, seeing as I’m a dead man who’ll soon disappear. I’ll leave you some words to chew on, but I won’t lend you a hand outside of that.”

His words weren’t too cold nor too kind. They were unmistakably his remarks as my master.

“What say we head back, Kanami? You must be fairly tuckered out, right?”

“Yeah, I guess I am.”

“You almost entirely mastered a whole school of bladecraft and it only tired you out a bit. Boy is that unfair.”

“That weirdly gets under your skin, huh, Lorwen?”

“It’d get under anybody’s skin at least a little. That’s just how unfair it is.”

As we bantered, we were about to exit Floor 30 when I noticed how thin his magic energy had gotten.

“Lorwen,” I stammered. “Am I imagining it or has your magic energy gotten weaker?”

This was different from expending magic energy. It wasn’t that there was less of it. The magic energy itself had gotten thinner, and the most apt way to describe it was “weakened.”

“That could be. Looks like teaching you was more fun than I’d have guessed. That was so fulfilling,” he said, smiling faintly and leaving it at that.

He was walking ahead of me, and from behind I could see that he was swaying feebly.

“I...see.”

I understood now. In the space of a few hours, we had erased one of the regrets in his heart. And I also understood how exceedingly easy the deal we’d struck to resolve his lingering attachments was. The hurdles in the way of achieving his heart’s desire were incredibly low. It probably wouldn’t take much at all for him to vanish from this world. But that wasn’t a sad thing. Not when vanishing was his ultimate desire and the end point of a happy life. As such, I couldn’t say anything more than that.

I couldn’t do anything but mumble those two words and keep following in his footsteps.

◆◆◆◆◆

Following that Dungeon dive with Lorwen, I headed alone to where I figured Palinchron was in order to give him a progress report on our little deal. I also had to report how I’d unilaterally decided to make Lorwen a guest of Epic Seeker. While I was guildmaster, the true top echelon was the submasters, veteran members that they were. Third, I wanted an explanation as to why he’d signed me up for the Brawl without asking me first. Lastly, I planned to question him about my mind and body too. I’d contemplated asking him to heal me, as his forte was mental magic, but I shook my head and put aside the idea right away. There was no doubt that Palinchron was hiding stuff from me. I didn’t trust him enough to be able to take that option. I couldn’t trust him unconditionally. Not anymore.

I had a lot to talk about. I recalled the directions Snow had told me as I walked. My destination was the foot of a mountain at the edge of Laoravia. There lay the villa of Rayle Thenks, the third of the three submasters and the man who’d saved me from the big fire alongside Palinchron. Mr. Rayle was Palinchron’s best friend, and it seemed Palinchron was borrowing his place while he was active in Laoravia.

As I walked through town, the number of people around gradually diminished. It looked as though the villa had been built in an outlying district. From what I’d heard, it was a lavish home, so I was slightly looking forward to paying a visit.

I continued walking down the desolate road, until at last I reached the villa. Or more precisely, the ruins of said villa.

“Huh? What the hell? This is the place, right?”

The villa had collapsed. None of its stone walls were left standing, and the pillars that had formerly propped the building up lay broken. The belongings inside weren’t intact either; everything had been destroyed. Obviously, the roof was gone as well, baring the interior to the elements. A number of people were running restlessly around nearby. These were the chamberlains and butlers and so on, as well as buff workers who looked to be in the construction business. From the snippets of the conversations I overheard, I could tell they were currently disposing of the debris and rebuilding.

I spotted the person who was giving them orders and drew closer. He was a man with countless scars on his face—the owner of this villa, Mr. Rayle. Himself a powerhouse, he picked up on my presence and looked my way, a little hostility on his face, which soon melted when he saw it was me.

“Oh, it’s you, huh? Thanks for coming,” he said, welcoming me with an amicable expression.

Despite being so obviously stretched thin, he’d greeted me with a smile. This was a man with a sturdy heart. He had more grit than two other submasters I could name.

“What on earth happened here?”

“Oh, nothing, just got hit by a small little assault.”

“An assault? What kind of attack could cause all this?”

Judging by the fallout, I thought they must have gotten attacked by a dragon or something. But his reply was even scarier than that, and in more ways than one.

“We got wrecked by a single girl.”

“Huh? A girl? You’re pulling my leg, right?”

“One girl did this. The girl called Diablo Sith. By her hand, this place became vacant land,” he said smilingly.

He’d come to terms with it, but this was no laughing matter to me.

“Diablo Sith?!”

She was one of the two overpowered girls. Her emotionally unstable outbursts and her way-too-pretty tear-stained face had made quite the impression on me.

Mr. Rayle seemed to know something about her, so I asked him, “Who or what is she?”

“Hmm...it was like she was an assassin with an axe to grind against Palinchron. The guy’s incurred quite a few people’s enmity, see. Stuff like this happens all the time. But then again, the mansion crumbling to the ground’s a first.”

“An assassin? Don’t assassins kill sneakily in the dead of night? So how’d it get like this?”

“Yeah, at first it was like that. But when he gave her the slip, she got revenge by completely destroying the mansion before going back.”

“Wait, what? She destroyed it in revenge... What?!”

I couldn’t believe what he’d said, but then I thought back to what she’d been like when I first bumped into her, and suddenly it seemed plausible.

“If I recall correctly, she said Palinchron had slashed her torso. I’m sure that must be why.”

“He slashed her? He’s never up to any good, that guy. I mean really.”

After learning that Palinchron was behaving as poorly as she was, I chose not to feel any sympathy for him.

“Uh, so is Palinchron not around here anymore, or...”

“He’s not even in the country anymore, let alone this mansion. He ended up jumping a bit ahead of schedule and going to Laoravia’s suzerain territory early. He pulled a runner with a smile on his face and a spring in his step.”

“With a smile on his face, huh? Leaving me in the lurch. I was in the middle of a deal with him.”

“That, you don’t gotta worry about. I can pinch-hit for all the main points. Your ‘deal’ being the thing about slaying the Guardian, right?”

“Ah, yes, that’s right.”

“Did ya kill the thing already? I figure if you show me the magic gem as proof, I’ll spill the beans.”

“No, not yet. I got to the floor and met him, but...it didn’t look like I could beat him.”

“So you succeeded in summoning it but can’t kill it. I see. Then the Guardian of Floor 30 really is cooperative with the one who reaches it.”

He’d accurately surmised my situation from the little information I’d given him.

“You already know? You know that the Guardian isn’t just some monster?”

“Yeah, I do...and it’s a secret known by the Dungeon Alliance as well.” From his tone, it seemed he was pretty well-informed about the Dungeon. And about me.

“You must know about them too, Mr. Rayle. About the Guardian...about my bangle...and about Lastiara Whoseyards and Diablo Sith.”

“Yep. I do indeed know about your bangle. Palinchron’s a malicious guy at heart. He didn’t say anything, but he must’ve been enjoying how much you were sweating. You know what, I’ll tell you what I can,” he said, picking up on what I was getting at.

If it had been Palinchron, he would’ve picked up on what I was getting at—and seized that opportunity to stoke my anxiety further. Maybe the fact he was at Laoravia’s beck and call was just sparing me some grief.

“I’ll start from the beginning. Number one, you really do have the bangle to thank for maintaining the life you currently enjoy in this world. If you lose it, every ounce of happiness you have here will crumble away, and that’s a fact. Protecting that bangle is for your own sake as much as anything else’s. As for those two girls—Lastiara Whoseyards and Diablo Sith—I don’t wanna tell you about them, as it’ll upset you. I know that if you learn the truth, it’d start weighing on you heavily. And make no mistake, you will suffer for it. You’ll lose your happy life and start walking the path of hardship. Palinchron may think that’s just fine, but personally, I recommend you stay far, far away from it. That path isn’t the path a kid as good-hearted as you should go down.”

“So you don’t deny that those two have some kind of connection to me.”

“I’m neither confirming nor denying it.”

“Nor are you denying that these bangles are altering my memories, and Maria’s too.”

“I’m not confirming or denying that either. But please don’t misunderstand. The memories that are sealed away are terrible ones. In order to give you two a happy life, the memories that you don’t need have been made fuzzier. Think of it as a sort of therapy. It was through that process that you two attained happiness. A life where you’re not on the run from anything, where you’ve got nothing to fear. You’re truly so much happier than before, it’s no contest...and people exist to be happy. Especially kids like you and Mar-Mar.”

I didn’t think he could be lying. Though it was rude of me, I was double-checking via Layered Dimension, and looking at things such as his body temperature and heart rate and so on, I saw none of the telltale signs.

“Surely you’ve got some small inkling of how tragic the day of that fire was? How hard it was for your sister Maria to endure? Looking at her eyes should give you an idea. If you regain your memories of that fire, your sister will have to face the agonizing and miserable truth...but if you yield to those bangles, you two will be able to keep the happiness you have now. That alone, I can guarantee you. I crafted the perfect plan to make sure of it. Stay on this path, and you get to lead a life as a hero of Laoravia where you want for nothing, and your sister will be happy too.”

From his tone, it was clear that he was truly looking out for me from the bottom of his heart. He was putting forth every effort to give us happiness. And once he threw my sister into the mix, I was left without a paddle. I could make all sorts of compromises if it only affected me, but I couldn’t if it affected the sister I loved so dearly. If it was what was best for her, I’d agree to it.

“If you still screw up the will to learn the whole truth despite all that, however, it’s a different story. I’ll tell you everything and make you two unhappy, if that’s what you want, and I’ll abandon all my plans. Or rather, ‘I’ll move on to the next plan’ is, I suppose, more accurate.”

Thus he gave me my second option. And the two choices before me were a difficult decision because their consequences were so apparent.

Mr. Rayle didn’t stop there. He also explained the significance behind my deal. “In our eyes, the slaying of the Guardian is a yardstick. If you’ve grown strong enough in body and mind to be able to take down such an entity—and if you still end up wanting to change your current situation after defeating that entity—then I’ve got no qualms about telling you the truth. I’ll lay it all out there. That’s what the deal is about.”

I didn’t sense any perfidy or malice in any of what he’d said. Unlike Palinchron, I could trust this man.

“I guess that’s about all I can tell you.”

“Thank you. You’ve explained a hundred times more than he ever did.”

“Palinchron didn’t even tell you a hundredth of what I just did?” He sighed. “He never changes.”

I couldn’t thank him enough. Thanks to him, I got a rough window into my current predicament. I also asked him to explain why they’d signed me up for the Brawl. Apparently, that was another part of his plan. He left the decision of whether or not to participate up to me. And as for Lorwen and Reaper staying at Epic Seeker, he agreed to it readily.

With that, I’d told him everything I could, and since he was busy with the work of repairing his mansion, we couldn’t talk for very long anyway. I thanked him and left without delay.

On my way back, I consolidated what I knew. To summarize, Maria and I had some sorrowful past that Palinchron was concealing from us, though his reasons remained unclear. Snow also knew that, but her taciturn nature meant she stopped at a vague warning. And finally, there was Mr. Rayle, who sincerely believed that keeping the truth hidden was key to our happiness. But he was also conniving in a way, because he’d formulated a plan to set me up as the hero of Epic Seeker. Maybe if I regained my memories, I’d stop being that hero.

It wasn’t enough. I simply didn’t have enough information yet. Our harrowing past was still shrouded in mist. I assumed that those two girls must have something to do with it. Lastiara had called Maria her friend. Maybe Maria and I had once been friends or allies with them. I could infer that based on how Diablo Sith had acted. But Mr. Rayle was opposed to me returning to their side. He’d said those two would be a burden on me, and that reconciling with them would be a “path of hardship.” Perhaps they were at least part of what had caused our misfortune.

I poured my all into trying to piece it together. After Maria and I had stumbled into this world, I must have started going by the alias “Sieg.” Back then, Lastiara and Dia must have been comrades of ours. But a series of unfortunate events had triggered that fateful fire, leaving the party scattered. Epic Seeker then took us under their wing. The chances were good that that was when Maria injured her eyes too.

Wait...that doesn’t make sense. Why was I the only one who went by an alias like “Sieg”? Lastiara called Maria by her real name. If I was going by an alias, why wouldn’t I make my sister do so too?

Actually, maybe it’s not that weird. Maybe the bangle prevented me from realizing that the name Maria is an alias? Could Maria’s real name be different? No, that’s...

But her real name being different was what made the most sense to me. Another thing that stood out to me as weird was the fact I’d been Dungeon diving back then too. The reason I was diving was to cover the costs of Maria’s treatment and to gain strength befitting the guildmaster of Epic Seeker. Would the siblings who ended up in a whole new world really enter the Dungeon, with the risks that entailed? What reason could we have had? I couldn’t imagine it was to gain the strength to defend ourselves. Not when the Dungeon itself was the most perilous place in all the land. It didn’t make sense to throw ourselves into the lap of danger in order to avoid danger. Did we do it for money, maybe? No...if our goal was to earn a living, there was no need to fixate on the Dungeon. There were plenty of jobs out there. What other reason could there be? To pay for Maria’s treatment?

In order to cover her medical expenses, I needed a lot of money fast, and it was for that purpose that I’d been diving—I’d understand if that was the case. But that didn’t gel with the sorrowful past that needed erasing or the day of the fire. It was the fire that had blinded Maria, and my memories had been sealed to hide whatever had happened.

Hold on a sec. Something’s not adding up about that either. If that were true, then why not just block her memories as opposed to both of ours? Wouldn’t hiding my memories be pointless? Did something bad happen to me too? Something as bad as Maria’s blinding?

There was no way Mr. Rayle would mess with my memories for no reason. There had to be a reason, but I just couldn’t see what it could be. I still lacked the information I needed. I could ponder until the cows came home, but it wouldn’t give me an answer I could be certain of. Was regaining my memories really what I ought to do?

For some reason, I was gradually losing confidence. After all, I hadn’t sensed any ill will from any of them—not from Palinchron or Mr. Rayle or Snow, nor from Lastiara or Diablo Sith. From what I could tell, they all had good intentions. And they were all acting for my sake. That was what was so hard to understand. It was all so...forgiving. So lax. Nobody wished me any harm, and there was no real danger anywhere. My state of affairs was too unthreatening, and I was too happy.

But am I really gonna dig up my and Maria’s dark memories? Really?

I got the sensation that someone was saying, “Why don’t you just stay the course?” I heard the whisper in my ear. “If you keep to this road, you’ll be able to safely attain happiness.” It even appealed to the kid inside me, telling me I could become a hero.

I kept walking, spurred forward by that invisible something giving me an encouraging pat on the back. When I arrived at Epic Seeker, I was greeted by my comrades. Strolling through the corridor, our members started talking to me with smiles on their faces. They believed in me wholeheartedly. Meanwhile, Snow was waiting for me in my office. And when I strained my ears, I could hear Reaper and Lorwen kicking up a commotion. It sounded like they were having fun. Up the stairs, my baby sister was happy and safe. What more could I ask for?

And yet I was bleeding. Drops of red, dripping from my clenched fist.

“What’s wrong, Kanami?” asked my sister, who was sitting atop her bed.

“Oh, no. It’s... It’s nothing.”

It was nothing. I needed it to be nothing. If I tripped up and strayed from the rail tracks, I’d be consigning her to a life of misery. And yet, it was also true that my gut was pleading with me to remove the bangle. If removing it would clear up these headaches, this sense of discomfort, and this rage I couldn’t explain, I had half a mind to do it. Little by little, my hand drew closer to the bangle. Little by little...little by little...

But right before my hand was about to touch it, I turned pale as a sheet. I felt a fierce chill down to my toes, racked by the fear that I was about to lose something more precious than life itself. My whole body froze up, and my hand wouldn’t get any closer.

“Are... Are you okay, Kanami? You don’t look so good.”

“Yeah, uh, yeah, I’m okay. I’m just a little sleepy.”

I collapsed into bed. My head was running hot. I hadn’t ruminated particularly deeply, and yet my head felt so heavy and stuffy. It was almost like my thoughts were bound by chains. I couldn’t think freely. Even if I tried to move forward, those chains would hold me back.

“I’m...slee...py...”

My world turned steadily blacker. My hand had failed to reach my bangle, and I’d lost my strength. At the same time, my consciousness was falling toward the bottom of the deep dark.

◆◆◆◆◆

Is this...a dream?

My fingertips felt as heavy as lead, and I couldn’t lift my arms. My legs were stuck in something, my body deprived of any freedom to move. It was like I was immersed in a muddy mire. I couldn’t even open my eyes, nor was I permitted to stir in the slightest. That was how deep the darkness I was floating in was. Then, a voice came from the void.

“Ah, I don’t care what ends up happening to you. That being said, your life going that smoothly does piss me off, so...”

A blurry figure appeared behind my eyelids. The silhouette was barely audible, but I could never mistake the owner of that voice. It was Palinchron Regacy.

I was now certain that this was a dream—a dream of the past. It was the memory of a defeat. The recollection had been triggered by some action I’d taken before falling asleep. I was remembering the words that Palinchron had imposed upon me. The curse. In the darkness, the flickering figure continued.

“Let’s make it so you value that bangle over your own life. After all, I do need ya to make protecting it priority number one. Hope ya don’t mind if that directive gets seared deep into your psyche.”

I was being shown all of the answers.

“Hm, I know. Why don’t I set it at the same level of importance as Aikawa Hitaki? That way I can rest assured he won’t touch it.”

He was saying diabolical shit without compunction as he made his evil magic energy creep into my body. The energy crawled around inside, meddling with my mind. Then the silhouette handed me something.

“Here, laddie. Or ‘Kanami.’ Put it on.”

And I took it. The me in the darkness took it. The light but sturdy bangle. It sat in the palm of my hand, and it felt heavier than its actual weight. It was like it was more precious to me than my life.

“That bangle is the next thing that you need to be protecting. Try overcoming the Vigesimal and Trigesimal Trials with that on. I’ve got faith you’re the one who can do it, pal,” he said with a smile.

“I’m just gonna have you think stuff that’s not strictly true” my ass. “I ain’t gonna touch the core of Aikawa Kanami” my ass. This was unforgivable. I knew that the winner took the spoils, and even if this was a matter of course from Palinchron’s point of view, I’d never forgive him. Even though I couldn’t move an inch, blood continued to drip from my clenched fist. That pain was forcing me to remember. Do not look past this injustice, it was telling me. Whatever you do, do not forgive and forget. Do not let this man, Palinchron Regacy, off the hook.

But this was a memory of the past. That sentiment would not linger past the memory I was watching play out. All I could do was lie there and dream it, this distant dream. And I knew that because I dreamed this dream every night. Once I woke up, I’d forget everything I saw. That was how it worked. When I opened my eyes, I’d wonder about the bleeding from my palm and try to remember my dream, only to find myself unable to, try as I might.

That was why I had no choice but to place my hopes not in myself, but in another. If I did now, my thoughts and feelings wouldn’t go in vain. I was able to convey this wrath I felt to the girl to whom I was linked. And while she was not the most dependable of people, that was better than telling no one.

Ba-dump.

Through the emblem on my neck, my thoughts flowed into a certain little girl: Don’t play with people’s futures! Don’t let his lies go unanswered! Don’t get what you want mixed up!

Please, I thought, hear my screams! And then send these thoughts back to me!

Please, Reaper!!!